<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--
  Content Structure: 

  <entry>
    <type></type>
    <question>
    </question>
    <answer>
    </answer>
  </entry>
-->
<entries>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Question</type>
    <question>
More Technical Questions
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Given two linked list, return a list that contains all elements that are in the intersection of both.
⏵ What tools do you use for version control and collaboration on code projects?
⏵ What are some best practices for ensuring data security in a software solution?
⏵ Can you explain the difference between RESTful and SOAP web services?
⏵ How do you ensure that your solutions are scalable and maintainable?
⏵ Can you explain the concept of continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD)?
⏵ How do you approach testing and quality assurance for the solutions you develop?
⏵ Can you explain the concept of serverless computing and its benefits?
⏵ Have you ever had to deal with a security breach or vulnerability in a system you were responsible for? If so, how did you handle it?
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Question</type>
    <question>
More Behaviour Questions
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Can you share an experience when you could not achieve your goals on a project?
⏵ Have you ever led a team through a complicated situation? 
⏵ What would your first three months in the position look like if we hire you?
⏵ What project have you successfully executed and are proudest about finishing?
⏵ Tell us about a time when you failed to achieve a goal or desired result.
⏵ Tell me about a time you created something from nothing.
⏵ Describe a time when you had to tell a customer "no".
⏵ Have you ever had to troubleshoot an issue in a production environment? If so, how did you handle it?
⏵ What is the most complex technical problem you have solved for a client? How did you approach it?
⏵ Can you provide an example of when you had to learn a new technology quickly to solve a customer’s problem?
⏵ Describe your experience with cloud platforms like AWS, Azure, or Google Cloud Platform.
⏵ How do you stay up-to-date with the latest trends and advancements in technology?
⏵ Describe a situation where you had to work closely with non-technical stakeholders to deliver a technical solution.
⏵ What is your process for creating clear and concise documentation for both technical and non-technical users?
⏵ How do you prioritize tasks when working on multiple projects simultaneously?
⏵ Describe a time when you had to adapt a solution due to changing requirements or constraints.
⏵ How do you handle situations where a client may not be satisfied with the technical solution you have provided?
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Introduction</type>
    <question>
Tips
    </question>
    <answer>
TSE #1 - Troubleshooting and Coding:
⏵ Focus on your strong analytical and troubleshooting skills, your proficiency in coding, and your experience in developing and debugging complex systems. 
⏵ Mention any significant projects where you've successfully identified and resolved issues.

TSE #2 - Technical and Customer Aptitude:
⏵ Emphasize your technical knowledge, especially relating to Google Cloud Platform (GCP) and other relevant technologies. 
⏵ Highlight your customer service philosophy, experience in providing technical support, and any instances where you've gone above and beyond to help customers or improve a product based on feedback.

TSE #3 - System Design and General Cognitive Assessment:
⏵ Share your experience with system architecture and design, focusing on projects where you've designed scalable and efficient systems. 
⏵ Mention how you approach problem-solving, your ability to think critically and creatively, and your eagerness to tackle complex challenges that drive innovation.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Introduction</type>
    <question>
Example Introduction for TSE #1 - Troubleshooting and Coding
    </question>
    <answer>
Hello, I am ____.

I've been working in IT development for over 20 years, mainly with banking and finance sector. 

Currrently, I work at Tata Consultancy Services as a Solution Architect role. They have assigned me to two projects.

The 1st project is the Loan Origination migration in Westpac. 
I helped the team to study a new vendor product, complete the proof of concept and create the framework for their integration development.
The project gave me a chance to learn a new architecture requirement and design the ways on using the vendor product in the Loan Origination.
The primary language used in the project was Java, and the vendor product is Lightbend Kalix.

After one year in Westpac project, the contract finished. 
TCS assigned me to a RamsayHealth project for their intergration and API management development on Cloud platforms.
During this time, I've learnt to develop application on Cloud.
The primary language used in the project was JavaScript, and the cloud platforms are GCP and AWS.
I learnt to use Anthos, APIGEE, Kubernetes to build up a multicloud platforms for RamsayHealth.

Before TCS employment, I was in HSBC as a technical lead in API and Integration domain for over 10 years. 
The last rile was to lead the team in China and India for the Core Engineering Platform for mircoservices development.
I was so grateful to work in such a global company so that 
I could meet different people in different business domain around the world 
as well as involve in many challenging entreprise projects, covering from backend, to middleware, frontend, and DevOps implementation.

I'm excited to take this interview opportunity, 
because I'm looking forward to using what I know about technology and problem-solving to help Google create new and better services for people around the world.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Introduction</type>
    <question>
Example Introduction for TSE #2 - Technical and Customer aptitude
    </question>
    <answer>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Introduction</type>
    <question>
Example Introduction for TSE #3 - System Design and General Cognitive assessment
    </question>
    <answer>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Keyword</type>
    <question>
Noun
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Effort, Factor
⏵ Time, Cost, Scope
⏵ Peer, Colleague, Teammate
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Keyword</type>
    <question>
Verb
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Prepare, Construct, Develop
⏵ Collaborate, Coordinate, Manage, Coach, Lead, Drive
⏵ Suggest, Recommend
⏵ Publish, Subscribe
⏵ Schedule / Hold a meeting
⏵ Escalate to _____
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Keyword</type>
    <question>
Adjective
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Loose Coupled, Tightly Coupled, Internal, External
⏵ Advantage, Disadvantage, Benefit, Drawback
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Key Sentences to Introduce Yourself at a Job Interview in English
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Good morning/afternoon. My name is ______ and I want to thank you for this opportunity.
⏵ Hello! My name is _______ and it’s a pleasure for me to be here.
⏵ Good morning/afternoon. I’m _______ and I want to thank you for taking me into consideration for this position.
⏵ Hello! My name is _______ and I’m glad you called me because I really want to work for this company.
⏵ Hi! My name is ________ and I’m here because I think I have the profile you’re looking for.
⏵ Hello! My name is _______ and first of all I want to congratulate you for making this company capable of offering a top quality service!
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Asking Someone to Repeat a Question
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ I’m sorry. Would you please repeat the question?
⏵ Excuse me, I didn’t hear you. Can you please say that again?
⏵ Would you please say that again?
⏵ Could you please repeat the question and speak a little bit harder?
⏵ Sorry, I didn’t understand you. Could you please say that again?
⏵ I’m sorry, I didn’t hear the last part. Can you repeat it, please?
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Emphasizing Your Strengths
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ I think I’m the right choice for this job because I know how to…
⏵ My (mention a set of skills relevant for the job) will allow me to do this easily.
⏵ I’m very good at ________ and that’s why I think I’ll be able to handle this position. (Fill the blank space with the one you consider is your best strength.)
⏵ I’d love to work here because I _______.
⏵ I think my ________, my _________ and my __________ make me perfect for this job.
⏵ I can say my top 3 skills are: ________, _________ and _________.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Thanking the Interviewer at the End of the Interview in English
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Thank you very much for your time. I’ll be waiting for your call!
⏵ I want you to know that I’m very thankful for this.
⏵ Before I leave I want to thank you for the opportunity. I hope we see each other again soon!
⏵ I wanted to thank you before I leave. I hope I have the profile you’re looking for.
⏵ It was a pleasure meeting you and then again I want to thank you for having me here!
⏵ I want to thank you one last time and I’ll be expecting your call!
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Some other sentences for a job interview in English 
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ I’ve been looking for this position for a long time.
⏵ I love the idea of working here because I enjoy _______.
⏵ This is what I always wanted to do and I know I can do it very well.
⏵ I’m glad I was recommended by _______ for this position!
⏵ I’m glad I saw this job post because I’m very excited about the idea of working for this company.
⏵ You can expect nothing but proficiency and excellent results if you hire me.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++⏵ ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
</entries>
