<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bank>
  <topic>PDE10 - Brain Dump</topic>
  <!--
    Reference:

    https://gcp-examquestions.com/google-professional-data-engineer-practice-exam-part-1/
    https://sdhyani0705.medium.com/professional-data-engineer-gcp-exam-question-27a5123bdca9
    https://www.passnexam.com/google/professional-data-engineer/2
    https://www.examtopics.com/discussions/google/view/16730-exam-professional-data-engineer-topic-1-question-17/
    https://www.dumpspedia.com/professional-data-engineer-google-professional-data-engineer-exam-dumps.html
    https://www.lead2pass.com/downloadable/download/sample/sample_id/7072/
    https://www.itexams.com/exam/Professional-Data-Engineer

  -->
  <!-- STRUCTURE DEFINITION:
  <entry>
    <question>XXX</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>XXX</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry> 
  -->
  <entry>
    <question>You are building new real-time data warehouse for your company and will use Google BigQuery streaming inserts. There is no guarantee that data will only be sent in once but you do have a unique ID for each row of data and an event timestamp. You want to ensure that duplicates are not included while interactively querying data. Which query type should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Include ORDER BY DESK on timestamp column and LIMIT to 1.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use GROUP BY on the unique ID column and timestamp column and SUM on the values.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the LAG window function with PARTITION by unique ID along with WHERE LAG IS NOT NULL.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use the ROW_NUMBER window function with PARTITION by unique ID along with WHERE row equals 1.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing a basket abandonment system for an ecommerce company. The system will send a message to a user based on these rules:
- No interaction by the user on the site for 1 hour
- Has added more than $30 worth of products to the basket
- Has not completed a transaction

You use Google Cloud Dataflow to process the data and decide if a message should be sent. How should you design the pipeline?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a fixed-time window with a duration of 60 minutes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a sliding time window with a duration of 60 minutes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use a session window with a gap time duration of 60 minutes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a global window with a time based trigger with a delay of 60 minutes.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is migrating their 30-node Apache Hadoop cluster to the cloud. They want to re-use Hadoop jobs they have already created and minimize the management of the cluster as much as possible. They also want to be able to persist data beyond the life of the cluster. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Google Cloud Dataflow job to process the data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Google Cloud Dataproc cluster that uses persistent disks for HDFS.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Hadoop cluster on Google Compute Engine that uses persistent disks. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud Dataproc cluster that uses the Google Cloud Storage connector. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Hadoop cluster on Google Compute Engine that uses Local SSD disks.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are deploying 10,000 new Internet of Things devices to collect temperature data in your warehouses globally. You need to process, store and analyze these very large datasets in real time. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Send the data to Google Cloud Datastore and then export to BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Send the data to Google Cloud Pub/Sub, stream Cloud Pub/Sub to Google Cloud Dataflow, and store the data in Google BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Send the data to Cloud Storage and then spin up an Apache Hadoop cluster as needed in Google Cloud Dataproc whenever analysis is required.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export logs in batch to Google Cloud Storage and then spin up a Google Cloud SQL instance, import the data from Cloud Storage, and run an analysis as needed.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is streaming real-time sensor data from their factory floor into Bigtable and they have noticed extremely poor performance. How should the row key be redesigned to improve Bigtable performance on queries that populate real-time dashboards?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a row key of the form {timestamp}.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a row key of the form {sensorid}.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a row key of the form {timestamp}#{sensorid}. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use a row key of the form {}#{sensorid}#{timestamp}.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Business owners at your company have given you a database of bank transactions. Each row contains the user ID, transaction type, transaction location, and transaction amount. They ask you to investigate what type of machine learning can be applied to the data. Which three machine learning applications can you use? (Choose three.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Supervised learning to determine which transactions are most likely to be fraudulent. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Unsupervised learning to determine which transactions are most likely to be fraudulent. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Clustering to divide the transactions into N categories based on feature similarity.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Supervised learning to predict the location of a transaction.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Reinforcement learning to predict the location of a transaction.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Unsupervised learning to predict the location of a transaction.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have Google Cloud Dataflow streaming pipeline running with a Google Cloud Pub/Sub subscription as the source. You need to make an update to the code that will make the new Cloud Dataflow pipeline incompatible with the current version. You do not want to lose any data when making this update. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Update the current pipeline and use the drain flag.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Update the current pipeline and provide the transform mapping JSON object.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a new pipeline that has the same Cloud Pub/Sub subscription and cancel the old pipeline. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a new pipeline that has a new Cloud Pub/Sub subscription and cancel the old pipeline.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company’s on-premises Apache Hadoop servers are approaching end-of-life, and IT has decided to migrate the cluster to Google Cloud Dataproc. A like-for- like migration of the cluster would require 50 TB of Google Persistent Disk per node. The CIO is concerned about the cost of using that much block storage. You want to minimize the storage cost of the migration. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Put the data into Google Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use preemptible virtual machines (VMs) for the Cloud Dataproc cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Tune the Cloud Dataproc cluster so that there is just enough disk for all data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Migrate some of the cold data into Google Cloud Storage, and keep only the hot data in Persistent Disk.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>An external customer provides you with a daily dump of data from their database. The data flows into Google Cloud Storage GCS as comma-separated values (CSV) files. You want to analyze this data in Google BigQuery, but the data could have rows that are formatted incorrectly or corrupted. How should you build this pipeline?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use federated data sources, and check data in the SQL query.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Enable BigQuery monitoring in Google Stackdriver and create an alert.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Import the data into BigQuery using the gcloud CLI and set max_bad_records to 0.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Run a Google Cloud Dataflow batch pipeline to import the data into BigQuery, and push errors to another dead-letter table for analysis.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are creating a model to predict housing prices. Due to budget constraints, you must run it on a single resource-constrained virtual machine. Which learning algorithm should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Linear regression</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Logistic classification</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Recurrent neural network </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Feedforward neural network</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is using WILDCARD tables to query data across multiple tables with similar names. The SQL statement is currently failing with the following error:
```
# Syntax error : Expected end of statement but got “-“ at [4:11] SELECT age
FROM
bigquery-public-data.noaa_gsod.gsod WHERE
age != 99
AND_TABLE_SUFFIX = ‘1929’ ORDER BY
age DESC
```

Which table name will make the SQL statement work correctly?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>'bigquery-public-data.noaa_gsod.gsod'</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>bigquery-public-data.noaa_gsod.gsod*</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>'bigquery-public-data.noaa_gsod.gsod'* </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>'bigquery-public-data.noaa_gsod.gsod*'</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You create an important report for your large team in Google Data Studio 360. The report uses Google BigQuery as its data source. You notice that visualizations are not showing data that is less than 1 hour old. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Disable caching by editing the report settings.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Disable caching in BigQuery by editing table details.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Refresh your browser tab showing the visualizations.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Clear your browser history for the past hour then reload the tab showing the virtualizations.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your weather app queries a database every 15 minutes to get the current temperature. The frontend is powered by Google App Engine and server millions of users. How should you design the frontend to respond to a database failure?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Issue a command to restart the database servers.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Retry the query with exponential backoff, up to a cap of 15 minutes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Retry the query every second until it comes back online to minimize staleness of data. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Reduce the query frequency to once every hour until the database comes back online.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Flowlogistic is rolling out their real-time inventory tracking system. The tracking devices will all send package-tracking messages, which will now go to a single Google Cloud Pub/Sub topic instead of the Apache Kafka cluster. A subscriber application will then process the messages for real-time reporting and store them in Google BigQuery for historical analysis. You want to ensure the package data can be analyzed over time. Which approach should you take?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Attach the timestamp on each message in the Cloud Pub/Sub subscriber application as they are received.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Attach the timestamp and Package ID on the outbound message from each publisher device as they are sent to Cloud Pub/Sub. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the NOW () function in BigQuery to record the event’s time.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the automatically generated timestamp from Cloud Pub/Sub to order the data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>MJTelco needs you to create a schema in Google Bigtable that will allow for the historical analysis of the last 2 years of records. Each record that comes in is sent every 15 minutes, and contains a unique identifier of the device and a data record. The most common query is for all the data for a given device for a given day. Which schema should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rowkey: date#device_id | Column data: data_point </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rowkey: date | Column data: device_id, data_point </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rowkey: device_id | Column data: date, data_point </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Rowkey: data_point | Column data: device_id, date </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rowkey: date#data_point | Column data: device_id</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>MJTelco is building a custom interface to share data. They have these requirements:
- They need to do aggregations over their petabyte-scale datasets.
- They need to scan specific time range rows with a very fast response time (milliseconds). 

Which combination of Google Cloud Platform products should you recommend?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore and Cloud Bigtable </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable and Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery and Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery and Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Given the record streams MJTelco is interested in ingesting per day, they are concerned about the cost of Google BigQuery increasing. MJTelco asks you to provide a design solution. They require a single large data table called tracking_table. Additionally, they want to minimize the cost of daily queries while performing fine-grained analysis of each day’s events. They also want to use streaming ingestion. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table called tracking_table and include a DATE column.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a partitioned table called tracking_table and include a TIMESTAMP column.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create sharded tables for each day following the pattern tracking_table_YYYYMMDD. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table called tracking_table with a TIMESTAMP column to represent the day.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>MJTelco’s Google Cloud Dataflow pipeline is now ready to start receiving data from the 50,000 installations. You want to allow Cloud Dataflow to scale its compute power up as required. Which Cloud Dataflow pipeline configuration setting should you update?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The zone</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The number of workers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The disk size per worker</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>The maximum number of workers</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to compose visualizations for operations teams with the following requirements: 
- The report must include telemetry data from all 50,000 installations for the most resent 6 weeks (sampling once every minute).
- The report must not be more than 3 hours delayed from live data.
- The actionable report should only show suboptimal links.
- Most suboptimal links should be sorted to the top.
- Suboptimal links can be grouped and filtered by regional geography.
- User response time to load the report must be less than 5 seconds.

Which approach meets the requirements?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the data into Google Sheets, use formulas to calculate a metric, and use filters/sorting to show only suboptimal links in a table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the data into Google BigQuery tables, write Google Apps Script that queries the data, calculates the metric, and shows only suboptimal rows in a table in Google Sheets.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the data into Google Cloud Datastore tables, write a Google App Engine Application that queries all rows, applies a function to derive the metric, and then renders results in a table using the Google charts and visualization API.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Load the data into Google BigQuery tables, write a Google Data Studio 360 report that connects to your data, calculates a metric, and then uses a filter expression to show only suboptimal rows in a table.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a large fast food restaurant chain with over 400,000 employees. You store employee information in Google BigQuery in a Users table consisting of a FirstName field and a LastName field. A member of IT is building an application and asks you to modify the schema and data in BigQuery so the application can query a FullName field consisting of the value of the FirstName field concatenated with a space, followed by the value of the LastName field for each employee. How can you make that data available while minimizing cost?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a view in BigQuery that concatenates the FirstName and LastName field values to produce the FullName.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a new column called FullName to the Users table. Run an UPDATE statement that updates the FullName column for each user with the concatenation of the FirstName and LastName values.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Google Cloud Dataflow job that queries BigQuery for the entire Users table, concatenates the FirstName value and LastName value for each user, and loads the proper values for FirstName, LastName, and FullName into a new table in BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery to export the data for the table to a CSV file. Create a Google Cloud Dataproc job to process the CSV file and output a new CSV file containing the proper values for FirstName, LastName and FullName. Run a BigQuery load job to load the new CSV file into BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for an economic consulting firm that helps companies identify economic trends as they happen. As part of your analysis, you use Google BigQuery to correlate customer data with the average prices of the 100 most common goods sold, including bread, gasoline, milk, and others. The average prices of these goods are updated every 30 minutes. You want to make sure this data stays up to date so you can combine it with other data in BigQuery as cheaply as possible. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the data every 30 minutes into a new partitioned table in BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Store and update the data in a regional Google Cloud Storage bucket and create a federated data source in BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store the data in Google Cloud Datastore. Use Google Cloud Dataflow to query BigQuery and combine the data programmatically with the data stored in Cloud Datastore.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store the data in a file in a regional Google Cloud Storage bucket. Use Cloud Dataflow to query BigQuery and combine the data programmatically with the data stored in Google Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>When you design a Google Cloud Bigtable schema it is recommended that you ...</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Avoid schema designs that are based on NoSQL concepts</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create schema designs that are based on a relational database design </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Avoid schema designs that require atomicity across rows</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create schema designs that require atomicity across rows</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following job types are supported by Cloud Dataproc (select 3 answers)?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Hive </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Pig</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>YARN </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Spark</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Why do you need to split a machine learning dataset into training data and test data?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>So you can try two different sets of features</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>To make sure your model is generalized for more than just the training data </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>To allow you to create unit tests in your code</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>So you can use one dataset for a wide model and one for a deep model</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What is the recommended action to do in order to switch between SSD and HDD storage for your Google Cloud Bigtable instance?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>create a third instance and sync the data from the two storage types via batch jobs </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>export the data from the existing instance and import the data into a new instance </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>run parallel instances where one is HDD and the other is SDD</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>the selection is final and you must resume using the same storage type</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>If you're running a performance test that depends upon Cloud Bigtable, all the choices except one below are recommended steps. Which is NOT a recommended step to follow?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Do not use a production instance.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Run your test for at least 10 minutes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Before you test, run a heavy pre-test for several minutes. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use at least 300 GB of data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What Dataflow concept determines when a Window's contents should be output based on certain criteria being met?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Sessions</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>OutputCriteria </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Windows</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Triggers</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Does Dataflow process batch data pipelines or streaming data pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Only Batch Data Pipelines</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Both Batch and Streaming Data Pipelines </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Only Streaming Data Pipelines</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>None of the above</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following statements about Legacy SQL and Standard SQL is not true?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Standard SQL is the preferred query language for BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>If you write a query in Legacy SQL, it might generate an error if you try to run it with Standard SQL. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>One difference between the two query languages is how you specify fully-qualified table names (i.e. table names that include their associated project name).</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>You need to set a query language for each dataset and the default is Standard SQL.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which Google Cloud Platform service is an alternative to Hadoop with Hive?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataflow </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>To run a TensorFlow training job on your own computer using Cloud Machine Learning Engine, what would your command start with?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>gcloud ml-engine local train</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>gcloud ml-engine jobs submit training</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>gcloud ml-engine jobs submit training local</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You can't run a TensorFlow program on your own computer using Cloud ML Engine .</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>The CUSTOM tier for Cloud Machine Learning Engine allows you to specify the number of which types of cluster nodes?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Workers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Masters, workers, and parameter servers </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Workers and parameter servers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Parameter servers</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What are two of the benefits of using denormalized data structures in BigQuery?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Reduces the amount of data processed, reduces the amount of storage required </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Increases query speed, makes queries simpler</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Reduces the amount of storage required, increases query speed</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Reduces the amount of data processed, increases query speed</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following statements is NOT true regarding Bigtable access roles?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Using IAM roles, you cannot give a user access to only one table in a project, rather than all tables in a project. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>To give a user access to only one table in a project, grant the user the Bigtable Editor role for that table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You can configure access control only at the project level.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>To give a user access to only one table in a project, you must configure access through your application.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Google Cloud Bigtable indexes a single value in each row. This value is called the _____.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>primary key </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>unique key </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>row key</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>master key</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which row keys are likely to cause a disproportionate number of reads and/or writes on a particular node in a Bigtable cluster (select 2 answers)?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>A sequential numeric ID</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>A timestamp followed by a stock symbol </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>A non-sequential numeric ID</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>A stock symbol followed by a timestamp</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these statements about BigQuery caching is true?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>By default, a query's results are not cached.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery caches query results for 48 hours.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Query results are cached even if you specify a destination table. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>There is no charge for a query that retrieves its results from cache.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How would you query specific partitions in a BigQuery table?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the DAY column in the WHERE clause</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the EXTRACT(DAY) clause</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use the _PARTITIONTIME pseudo-column in the WHERE clause </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use DATE BETWEEN in the WHERE clause</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>The Dataflow SDKs have been recently transitioned into which Apache service?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Apache Spark </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Apache Hadoop </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Apache Kafka </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Apache Beam</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following are feature engineering techniques? (Select 2 answers)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Hidden feature layers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Feature prioritization</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Crossed feature columns</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Bucketization of a continuous feature</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following are examples of hyperparameters? (Select 2 answers.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Number of hidden layers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Number of nodes in each hidden layer </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Biases</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Weights</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following is NOT a valid use case to select HDD (hard disk drives) as the storage for Google Cloud Bigtable?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You expect to store at least 10 TB of data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You will mostly run batch workloads with scans and writes, rather than frequently executing random reads of a small number of rows. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>You need to integrate with Google BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You will not use the data to back a user-facing or latency-sensitive application.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>For the best possible performance, what is the recommended zone for your Compute Engine instance and Cloud Bigtable instance?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Have the Compute Engine instance in the furthest zone from the Cloud Bigtable instance.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Have both the Compute Engine instance and the Cloud Bigtable instance to be in different zones. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Have both the Compute Engine instance and the Cloud Bigtable instance to be in the same zone. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Have the Cloud Bigtable instance to be in the same zone as all of the consumers of your data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>When a Cloud Bigtable node fails, _____ is lost.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>all data</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>no data</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>the last transaction </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>the time dimension</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>The _____ for Cloud Bigtable makes it possible to use Cloud Bigtable in a Cloud Dataflow pipeline.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataflow connector</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>DataFlow SDK</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BiqQuery API</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery Data Transfer Service</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Cloud Dataproc charges you only for what you really use with billing.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>month-by-month </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>minute-by-minute </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>week-by-week</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>hour-by-hour</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are developing a software application using Google's Dataflow SDK, and want to use conditional, for loops and other complex programming structures to create a branching pipeline. Which component will be used for the data processing operation?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>PCollection </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Transform </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipeline</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Sink API</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which is the preferred method to use to avoid hotspotting in time series data in Bigtable?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Field promotion </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Randomization </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Salting</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Hashing</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What are two of the characteristics of using online prediction rather than batch prediction?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>It is optimized to handle a high volume of data instances in a job and to run more complex models. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Predictions are returned in the response message.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Predictions are written to output files in a Cloud Storage location that you specify.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>It is optimized to minimize the latency of serving predictions.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are planning to use Google's Dataflow SDK to analyze customer data such as displayed below. Your project requirement is to extract only the customer name from the data source and then write to an output PCollection.
```
Tom,555 X street –
Tim,553 Y street –
Sam, 111 Z street –
```

Which operation is best suited for the above data processing requirement?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>ParDo</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Sink API</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Source API</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Data extraction</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these numbers are adjusted by a neural network as it learns from a training dataset (select 2 answers)?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Weights</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Biases</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Continuous features </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Input values</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following is not possible using primitive roles?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Give a user viewer access to BigQuery and owner access to Google Compute Engine instances. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Give UserA owner access and UserB editor access for all datasets in a project.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Give a user access to view all datasets in a project, but not run queries on them.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Give GroupA owner access and GroupB editor access for all datasets in a project.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have enabled the free integration between Firebase Analytics and Google BigQuery. Firebase now automatically creates a new table daily in BigQuery in the format app_events_YYYYMMDD. You want to query all of the tables for the past 30 days in legacy SQL. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use the TABLE_DATE_RANGE function</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the WHERE_PARTITIONTIME pseudo column</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use WHERE date BETWEEN YYYY-MM-DD AND YYYY-MM-DD</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use SELECT IF.(date ＞＝ YYYY-MM-DD AND date ＜＝ YYYY-MM-DD</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have a data pipeline with a Cloud Dataflow job that aggregates and writes time series metrics to Cloud Bigtable. This data feeds a dashboard used by thousands of users across the organization. You need to support additional concurrent users and reduce the amount of time required to write the data. Which two actions should you take? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Configure your Cloud Dataflow pipeline to use local execution</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Increase the maximum number of Cloud Dataflow workers by setting maxNumWorkers in PipelineOptions </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Increase the number of nodes in the Cloud Bigtable cluster</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Modify your Cloud Dataflow pipeline to use the Flatten transform before writing to Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Modify your Cloud Dataflow pipeline to use the CoGroupByKey transform before writing to Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work on a regression problem in a natural language processing domain, and you have 100M labeled exmaples in your dataset. You have randomly shuffled your data and split your dataset into train and test samples (in a 90/10 ratio). After you trained the neural network and evaluated your model on a test set, you discover that the root-mean-squared error (RMSE) of your model is twice as high on the train set as on the test set. How should you improve the performance of your model?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the share of the test sample in the train-test split.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Try to collect more data and increase the size of your dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Try out regularization techniques (e.g., dropout of batch normalization) to avoid overfitting.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the complexity of your model by, E.g., introducing an additional layer or increase sizing the size of vocabularies or n-grams used.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your infrastructure includes a set of YouTube channels. You have been tasked with creating a process for sending the YouTube channel data to Google Cloud for analysis. You want to design a solution that allows your world-wide marketing teams to perform ANSI SQL and other types of analysis on up-to-date YouTube channels log data. How should you set up the log data transfer into Google Cloud?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Storage Transfer Service to transfer the offsite backup files to a Cloud Storage Multi-Regional storage bucket as a final destination.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Storage Transfer Service to transfer the offsite backup files to a Cloud Storage Regional bucket as a final destination.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery Data Transfer Service to transfer the offsite backup files to a Cloud Storage Multi-Regional storage bucket as a final destination. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery Data Transfer Service to transfer the offsite backup files to a Cloud Storage Regional storage bucket as a final destination.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You receive data files in CSV format monthly from a third party. You need to cleanse this data, but every third month the schema of the files changes. Your requirements for implementing these transformations include:
- Executing the transformations on a schedule
- Enabling non-developer analysts to modify transformations
- Providing a graphical tool for designing transformations What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataprep to build and maintain the transformation recipes, and execute them on a scheduled basis </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load each month’s CSV data into BigQuery, and write a SQL query to transform the data to a standard schema. Merge the transformed tables together with a SQL query</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Help the analysts write a Cloud Dataflow pipeline in Python to perform the transformation. The Python code should be stored in a revision control system and modified as the incoming data’s schema changes</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Apache Spark on Cloud Dataproc to infer the schema of the CSV file before creating a Dataframe. Then implement the transformations in Spark SQL before writing the data out to Cloud Storage and loading into BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>As your organization expands its usage of GCP, many teams have started to create their own projects. Projects are further multiplied to accommodate different stages of deployments and target audiences. Each project requires unique access control configurations. The central IT team needs to have access to all projects. Furthermore, data from Cloud Storage buckets and BigQuery datasets must be shared for use in other projects in an ad hoc way. You want to simplify access control management by minimizing the number of policies. Which two steps should you take? Choose 2 answers.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Deployment Manager to automate access provision.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Introduce resource hierarchy to leverage access control policy inheritance.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create distinct groups for various teams, and specify groups in Cloud IAM policies.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Only use service accounts when sharing data for Cloud Storage buckets and BigQuery datasets.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>For each Cloud Storage bucket or BigQuery dataset, decide which projects need access. Find all the active members who have access to these projects, and create a Cloud IAM policy to grant access to all these users.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building an application to share financial market data with consumers, who will receive data feeds. Data is collected from the markets in real time. Consumers will receive the data in the following ways:
- Real-time event stream
- ANSI SQL access to real-time stream and historical data
- Batch historical exports Which solution should you use?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataflow, Cloud SQL, Cloud Spanner </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Pub/Sub, Cloud Storage, BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataproc, Cloud Dataflow, BigQuery </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Pub/Sub, Cloud Dataproc, Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your analytics team wants to build a simple statistical model to determine which customers are most likely to work with your company again, based on a few different metrics. They want to run the model on Apache Spark, using data housed in Google Cloud Storage, and you have recommended using Google Cloud Dataproc to execute this job. Testing has shown that this workload can run in approximately 30 minutes on a 15-node cluster, outputting the results into Google BigQuery. The plan is to run this workload weekly. How should you optimize the cluster for cost?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Migrate the workload to Google Cloud Dataflow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use pre-emptible virtual machines (VMs) for the cluster</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a higher-memory node so that the job runs faster</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use SSDs on the worker nodes so that the job can run faster</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to deploy additional dependencies to all of a Cloud Dataproc cluster at startup using an existing initialization action. Company security policies require that Cloud Dataproc nodes do not have access to the Internet so public initialization actions cannot fetch resources. What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy the Cloud SQL Proxy on the Cloud Dataproc master</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use an SSH tunnel to give the Cloud Dataproc cluster access to the Internet</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Copy all dependencies to a Cloud Storage bucket within your VPC security perimeter</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Resource Manager to add the service account used by the Cloud Dataproc cluster to the Network User role</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are a retailer that wants to integrate your online sales capabilities with different in-home assistants, such as Google Home. You need to interpret customer voice commands and issue an order to the backend systems. Which solutions should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Speech-to-Text API</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Natural Language API</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Dialogflow Enterprise Edition</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud AutoML Natural Language</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your financial services company is moving to cloud technology and wants to store 50 TB of financial timeseries data in the cloud. This data is updated frequently and new data will be streaming in all the time. Your company also wants to move their existing Apache Hadoop jobs to the cloud to get insights into this data. Which product should they use to store the data?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Google BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Google Cloud Storage </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Google Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are developing an application on Google Cloud that will automatically generate subject labels for users’ blog posts. You are under competitive pressure to add this feature quickly, and you have no additional developer resources. No one on your team has experience with machine learning. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Call the Cloud Natural Language API from your application. Process the generated Entity Analysis as labels.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Call the Cloud Natural Language API from your application. Process the generated Sentiment Analysis as labels.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Build and train a text classification model using TensorFlow. Deploy the model using Cloud Machine Learning Engine. Call the model from your application and process the results as labels.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Build and train a text classification model using TensorFlow. Deploy the model using a Kubernetes Engine cluster. Call the model from your application and process the results as labels.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You operate an IoT pipeline built around Apache Kafka that normally receives around 5000 messages per second. You want to use Google Cloud Platform to create an alert as soon as the moving average over 1 hour drops below 4000 messages per second. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Consume the stream of data in Cloud Dataflow using Kafka IO. Set a sliding time window of 1 hour every 5 minutes. Compute the average when the window closes, and send an alert if the average is less than 4000 messages.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Consume the stream of data in Cloud Dataflow using Kafka IO. Set a fixed time window of 1 hour. Compute the average when the window closes, and send an alert if the average is less than 4000 messages.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Kafka Connect to link your Kafka message queue to Cloud Pub/Sub. Use a Cloud Dataflow template to write your messages from Cloud Pub/Sub to Cloud Bigtable. Use Cloud Scheduler to run a script every hour that counts the number of rows created in Cloud Bigtable in the last hour. If that number falls below 4000, send an alert.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Kafka Connect to link your Kafka message queue to Cloud Pub/Sub. Use a Cloud Dataflow template to write your messages from Cloud Pub/Sub to BigQuery. Use Cloud Scheduler to run a script every five minutes that counts the number of rows created in BigQuery in the last hour. If that number falls below 4000, send an alert.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your organization has been collecting and analyzing data in Google BigQuery for 6 months. The majority of the data analyzed is placed in a time-partitioned table named events_partitioned. To reduce the cost of queries, your organization created a view called events, which queries only the last 14 days of data. The view is described in legacy SQL. Next month, existing applications will be connecting to BigQuery to read the events data via an ODBC connection. You need to ensure the applications can connect. Which two actions should you take? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a new view over events using standard SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a new partitioned table using a standard SQL query</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a new view over events_partitioned using standard SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a service account for the ODBC connection to use for authentication</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Google Cloud Identity and Access Management (Cloud IAM) role for the ODBC connectionand shared “events”</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You operate a logistics company, and you want to improve event delivery reliability for vehicle-based sensors. You operate small data centers around the world to capture these events, but leased lines that provide connectivity from your event collection infrastructure to your event processing infrastructure are unreliable, with unpredictable latency. You want to address this issue in the most cost-effective way. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy small Kafka clusters in your data centers to buffer events.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Have the data acquisition devices publish data to Cloud Pub/Sub.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Establish a Cloud Interconnect between all remote data centers and Google. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write a Cloud Dataflow pipeline that aggregates all data in session windows.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to move 2 PB of historical data from an on-premises storage appliance to Cloud Storage within six months, and your outbound network capacity is constrained to 20 Mb/sec. How should you migrate this data to Cloud Storage?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Transfer Appliance to copy the data to Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gsutil cp –J to compress the content being uploaded to Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a private URL for the historical data, and then use Storage Transfer Service to copy the data to Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use trickle or ionice along with gsutil cp to limit the amount of bandwidth gsutil utilizes to less than 20 Mb/sec so it does not interfere with the production traffic</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to automate execution of a multi-step data pipeline running on Google Cloud. The pipeline includes Cloud Dataproc and Cloud Dataflow jobs that have multiple dependencies on each other. You want to use managed services where possible, and the pipeline will run every day. Which tool should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>cron</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Composer</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Scheduler</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Workflow Templates on Cloud Dataproc</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have developed three data processing jobs. One executes a Cloud Dataflow pipeline that transforms data uploaded to Cloud Storage and writes results to BigQuery. The second ingests data from on-premises servers and uploads it to Cloud Storage. The third is a Cloud Dataflow pipeline that gets information from third-party data providers and uploads the information to Cloud Storage. You need to be able to schedule and monitor the execution of these three workflows and manually execute them when needed. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a Direct Acyclic Graph in Cloud Composer to schedule and monitor the jobs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Stackdriver Monitoring and set up an alert with a Webhook notification to trigger the jobs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Develop an App Engine application to schedule and request the status of the jobs using GCP API calls.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set up cron jobs in a Compute Engine instance to schedule and monitor the pipelines using GCP API calls.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are integrating one of your internal IT applications and Google BigQuery, so users can query BigQuery from the application’s interface. You do not want individual users to authenticate to BigQuery and you do not want to give them access to the dataset. You need to securely access BigQuery from your IT application. What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create groups for your users and give those groups access to the dataset</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Integrate with a single sign-on (SSO) platform, and pass each user’s credentials along with the query request</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a service account and grant dataset access to that account. Use the service account's private key to access the dataset</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a dummy user and grant dataset access to that user. Store the username and password for that user in a file on the files system, and use those credentials to access the BigQuery dataset</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing storage for 20 TB of text files as part of deploying a data pipeline on Google Cloud. Your input data is in CSV format. You want to minimize the cost of querying aggregate values for multiple users who will query the data in Cloud Storage with multiple engines. Which storage service and schema design should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Bigtable for storage. Install the HBase shell on a Compute Engine instance to query the Cloud Bigtable data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Bigtable for storage. Link as permanent tables in BigQuery for query.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Storage for storage. Link as permanent tables in BigQuery for query.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Storage for storage. Link as temporary tables in BigQuery for query.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are managing a Cloud Dataproc cluster. You need to make a job run faster while minimizing costs, without losing work in progress on your clusters. What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the cluster size with more non-preemptible workers.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the cluster size with preemptible worker nodes, and configure them to forcefully decommission.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the cluster size with preemptible worker nodes, and use Cloud Stackdriver to trigger a script to preserve work.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Increase the cluster size with preemptible worker nodes, and configure them to use graceful decommissioning.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing an Apache Beam pipeline to enrich data from Cloud Pub/Sub with static reference data from BigQuery. The reference data is small enough to fit in memory on a single worker. The pipeline should write enriched results to BigQuery for analysis. Which job type and transforms should this pipeline use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Batch job, PubSubIO, side-inputs</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Streaming job, PubSubIO, JdbcIO, side-outputs</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Streaming job, PubSubIO, BigQueryIO, side-inputs </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Streaming job, PubSubIO, BigQueryIO, side-outputs</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your globally distributed auction application allows users to bid on items. Occasionally, users place identical bids at nearly identical times, and different application servers process those bids. Each bid event contains the item, amount, user, and timestamp. You want to collate those bid events into a single location in real time to determine which user bid first. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a file on a shared file and have the application servers write all bid events to that file. Process the file with Apache Hadoop to identify which user bid first.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Have each application server write the bid events to Cloud Pub/Sub as they occur. Push the events from Cloud Pub/Sub to a custom endpoint that writes the bid event information into Cloud SQL. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set up a MySQL database for each application server to write bid events into. Periodically query each of those distributed MySQL databases and update a master MySQL database with bid event information.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Have each application server write the bid events to Google Cloud Pub/Sub as they occur. Use a pull subscription to pull the bid events using Google Cloud Dataflow. Give the bid for each item to the user in the bid event that is processed first.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to build a managed Hadoop system as your data lake. The data transformation process is composed of a series of Hadoop jobs executed in sequence. To accomplish the design of separating storage from compute, you decided to use the Cloud Storage connector to store all input data, output data, and intermediary data. However, you noticed that one Hadoop job runs very slowly with Cloud Dataproc, when compared with the on-premises bare-metal Hadoop environment (8-core nodes with 100-GB RAM). Analysis shows that this particular Hadoop job is disk I/O intensive. You want to resolve the issue. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Allocate sufficient memory to the Hadoop cluster, so that the intermediary data of that particular Hadoop job can be held in memory</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Allocate sufficient persistent disk space to the Hadoop cluster, and store the intermediate data of that particular Hadoop job on native HDFS</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Allocate more CPU cores of the virtual machine instances of the Hadoop cluster so that the networking bandwidth for each instance can scale up</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Allocate additional network interface card (NIC), and configure link aggregation in the operating system to use the combined throughput when working with Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are using Google BigQuery as your data warehouse. Your users report that the following simple query is running very slowly, no matter when they run the query:
```
SELECT country, state, city FROM [myproject:mydataset.mytable] GROUP BY country
```
You check the query plan for the query and see the following output in the Read section of Stage:1:

Partition or sample mode
- Use replacement in the partitioning: No
- Randomized split: Yes
- Random seed: `0`

Specify the partitioner method: Partition evenly
Specify number of folds to split evenly into: `3`

What is the most likely cause of the delay for this query?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Users are running too many concurrent queries in the system</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The [myproject:mydataset.mytable] table has too many partitions</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Either the state or the city columns in the [myproject:mydataset.mytable] table have too many NULL values</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Most rows in the [myproject:mydataset.mytable] table have the same value in the country column, causing data skew</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a manufacturing company that sources up to 750 different components, each from a different supplier. You’ve collected a labeled dataset that has on average 1000 examples for each unique component. Your team wants to implement an app to help warehouse workers recognize incoming components based on a photo of the component. You want to implement the first working version of this app (as Proof-Of-Concept) within a few working days. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Vision AutoML with the existing dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Vision AutoML, but reduce your dataset twice.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Vision API by providing custom labels as recognition hints.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Train your own image recognition model leveraging transfer learning techniques.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to set access to BigQuery for different departments within your company. Your solution should comply with the following requirements:
- Each department should have access only to their data.
- Each department will have one or more leads who need to be able to create and update tables and provide them to their team.
- Each department has data analysts who need to be able to query but not modify data. How should you set access to the data in BigQuery?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a dataset for each department. Assign the department leads the role of OWNER, and assign the data analysts the role of WRITER on their dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a dataset for each department. Assign the department leads the role of WRITER, and assign the data analysts the role of READER on their dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table for each department. Assign the department leads the role of Owner, and assign the data analysts the role of Editor on the project the table is in.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table for each department. Assign the department leads the role of Editor, and assign the data analysts the role of Viewer on the project the table is in.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You used Cloud Dataprep to create a recipe on a sample of data in a BigQuery table. You want to reuse this recipe on a daily upload of data with the same schema, after the load job with variable execution time completes. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a cron schedule in Cloud Dataprep.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an App Engine cron job to schedule the execution of the Cloud Dataprep job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the recipe as a Cloud Dataprep template, and create a job in Cloud Scheduler.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Export the Cloud Dataprep job as a Cloud Dataflow template, and incorporate it into a Cloud Composer job.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You’ve migrated a Hadoop job from an on-prem cluster to dataproc and GCS. Your Spark job is a complicated analytical workload that consists of many shuffing operations and initial data are parquet files (on average 200-400 MB size each). You see some degradation in performance after the migration to Dataproc, so you’d like to optimize for it. You need to keep in mind that your organization is very cost-sensitive, so you’d like to continue using Dataproc on preemptibles (with 2 non-preemptible workers only) for this workload. What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the size of your parquet files to ensure them to be 1 GB minimum.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Switch to TFRecords formats (appr. 200MB per file) instead of parquet files.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Switch from HDDs to SSDs, copy initial data from GCS to HDFS, run the Spark job and copy results back to GCS. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Switch from HDDs to SSDs, override the preemptible VMs configuration to increase the boot disk size.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your United States-based company has created an application for assessing and responding to user actions. The primary table’s data volume grows by 250,000 records per second. Many third parties use your application’s APIs to build the functionality into their own frontend applications. Your application’s APIs should comply with the following requirements:
- Single global endpoint
- ANSI SQL support
- Consistent access to the most up-to-date data What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Implement BigQuery with no region selected for storage or processing.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Implement Cloud Spanner with the leader in North America and read-only replicas in Asia and Europe.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Implement Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL with the master in North America and read replicas in Asia and Europe. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Implement Cloud Bigtable with the primary cluster in North America and secondary clusters in Asia and Europe.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You launched a new gaming app almost three years ago. You have been uploading log files from the previous day to a separate Google BigQuery table with the table name format LOGS_yyyymmdd. You have been using table wildcard functions to generate daily and monthly reports for all time ranges. Recently, you discovered that some queries that cover long date ranges are exceeding the limit of 1,000 tables and failing. How can you resolve this issue?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Convert all daily log tables into date-partitioned tables</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Convert the sharded tables into a single partitioned table</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Enable query caching so you can cache data from previous months</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create separate views to cover each month, and query from these views</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is selecting a system to centralize data ingestion and delivery. You are considering messaging and data integration systems to address the requirements. The key requirements are:
- The ability to seek to a particular offset in a topic, possibly back to the start of all data ever captured
- Support for publish/subscribe semantics on hundreds of topics
- Retain per-key ordering Which system should you choose?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Apache Kafka</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Pub/Sub</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Firebase Cloud Messaging</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to migrate a 2TB relational database to Google Cloud Platform. You do not have the resources to significantly refactor the application that uses this database and cost to operate is of primary concern. Which service do you select for storing and serving your data?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Spanner </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Firestore </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have data pipelines running on BigQuery, Cloud Dataflow, and Cloud Dataproc. You need to perform health checks and monitor their behavior, and then notify the team managing the pipelines if they fail. You also need to be able to work across multiple projects. Your preference is to use managed products of features of the platform. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Export the information to Cloud Stackdriver, and set up an Alerting policy</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Run a Virtual Machine in Compute Engine with Airflow, and export the information to Stackdriver</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the logs to BigQuery, and set up App Engine to read that information and send emails if you find a failure in the logs </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Develop an App Engine application to consume logs using GCP API calls, and send emails if you find a failure in the logs</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You use BigQuery as your centralized analytics platform. New data is loaded every day, and an ETL pipeline modifies the original data and prepares it for the final users. This ETL pipeline is regularly modified and can generate errors, but sometimes the errors are detected only after 2 weeks. You need to provide a method to recover from these errors, and your backups should be optimized for storage costs. How should you organize your data in BigQuery and store your backups?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Organize your data in a single table, export, and compress and store the BigQuery data in Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Organize your data in separate tables for each month, and export, compress, and store the data in Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Organize your data in separate tables for each month, and duplicate your data on a separate dataset in BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Organize your data in separate tables for each month, and use snapshot decorators to restore the table to a time prior to the corruption.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have several Spark jobs that run on a Cloud Dataproc cluster on a schedule. Some of the jobs run in sequence, and some of the jobs run concurrently. You need to automate this process. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud Dataproc Workflow Template</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an initialization action to execute the jobs</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a Directed Acyclic Graph in Cloud Composer</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Bash script that uses the Cloud SDK to create a cluster, execute jobs, and then tear down the cluster</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is currently setting up data pipelines for their campaign. For all the Google Cloud Pub/Sub streaming data, one of the important business requirements is to be able to periodically identify the inputs and their timings during their campaign. Engineers have decided to use windowing and transformation in Google Cloud Dataflow for this purpose. However, when testing this feature, they find that the Cloud Dataflow job fails for the all streaming insert. What is the most likely cause of this problem?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>They have not assigned the timestamp, which causes the job to fail</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>They have not set the triggers to accommodate the data coming in late, which causes the job to fail</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>They have not applied a global windowing function, which causes the job to fail when the pipeline is created</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>They have not applied a non-global windowing function, which causes the job to fail when the pipeline is created</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing a cloud-native historical data processing system to meet the following conditions:
- The data being analyzed is in CSV, Avro, and PDF formats and will be accessed by multiple analysis tools including Cloud Dataproc, BigQuery, and Compute Engine.
- A streaming data pipeline stores new data daily.
- Peformance is not a factor in the solution.
- The solution design should maximize availability.

How should you design data storage for this solution?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud Dataproc cluster with high availability. Store the data in HDFS, and peform analysis as needed.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store the data in BigQuery. Access the data using the BigQuery Connector or Cloud Dataproc and Compute Engine. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store the data in a regional Cloud Storage bucket. Aceess the bucket directly using Cloud Dataproc, BigQuery, and Compute Engine.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Store the data in a multi-regional Cloud Storage bucket. Access the data directly using Cloud Dataproc, BigQuery, and Compute Engine.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are deploying MariaDB SQL databases on GCE VM Instances and need to configure monitoring and alerting. You want to collect metrics including network connections, disk IO and replication status from MariaDB with minimal development effort and use StackDriver for dashboards and alerts. What should you do?
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install the OpenCensus Agent and create a custom metric collection application with a StackDriver exporter. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Place the MariaDB instances in an Instance Group with a Health Check.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Install the StackDriver Logging Agent and configure fluentd in_tail plugin to read MariaDB logs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install the StackDriver Agent and configure the MySQL plugin.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are working on a niche product in the image recognition domain. Your team has developed a model that is dominated by custom C++ TensorFlow ops your team has implemented. These ops are used inside your main training loop and are performing bulky matrix multiplications. It currently takes up to several days to train a model. You want to decrease this time significantly and keep the cost low by using an accelerator on Google Cloud. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud TPUs without any additional adjustment to your code.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud TPUs after implementing GPU kernel support for your customs ops. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud GPUs after implementing GPU kernel support for your customs ops. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Stay on CPUs, and increase the size of the cluster you’re training your model on.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have Cloud Functions written in Node.js that pull messages from Cloud Pub/Sub and send the data to BigQuery. You observe that the message processing rate on the Pub/Sub topic is orders of magnitude higher than anticipated, but there is no error logged in Stackdriver Log Viewer. What are the two most likely causes of this problem? Choose 2 answers.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Publisher throughput quota is too small.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Total outstanding messages exceed the 10-MB maximum.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Error handling in the subscriber code is not handling run-time errors properly. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The subscriber code cannot keep up with the messages.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>The subscriber code does not acknowledge the messages that it pulls.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <question>The marketing team at your organization provides regular updates of a segment of your customer dataset. The marketing team has given you a CSV with 1 million records that must be updated in BigQuery. When you use the UPDATE statement in BigQuery, you receive a quotaExceeded error. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Reduce the number of records updated each day to stay within the BigQuery UPDATE DML statement limit.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the BigQuery UPDATE DML statement limit in the Quota management section of the Google Cloud Platform Console.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Split the source CSV file into smaller CSV files in Cloud Storage to reduce the number of BigQuery UPDATE DML statements per BigQuery job. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Import the new records from the CSV file into a new BigQuery table. Create a BigQuery job that merges the new records with the existing records and writes the results to a new BigQuery table.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for an advertising company, and you’ve developed a Spark ML model to predict click-through rates at advertisement blocks. You’ve been developing everything at your on-premises data center, and now your company is migrating to Google Cloud. Your data center will be migrated to BigQuery. You periodically retrain your Spark ML models, so you need to migrate existing training pipelines to Google Cloud. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud ML Engine for training existing Spark ML models</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rewrite your models on TensorFlow, and start using Cloud ML Engine</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataproc for training existing Spark ML models, but start reading data directly from BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Spin up a Spark cluster on Compute Engine, and train Spark ML models on the data exported from BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are creating a new pipeline in Google Cloud to stream IoT data from Cloud Pub/Sub through Cloud Dataflow to BigQuery. While previewing the data, you notice that roughly 2% of the data appears to be corrupt. You need to modify the Cloud Dataflow pipeline to filter out this corrupt data. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a SideInput that returns a Boolean if the element is corrupt.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Add a ParDo transform in Cloud Dataflow to discard corrupt elements.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a Partition transform in Cloud Dataflow to separate valid data from corrupt data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a GroupByKey transform in Cloud Dataflow to group all of the valid data together and discard the rest.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a shipping company that has distribution centers where packages move on delivery lines to route them properly. The company wants to add cameras to the delivery lines to detect and track any visual damage to the packages in transit. You need to create a way to automate the detection of damaged packages and flag them for human review in real time while the packages are in transit. Which solution should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery machine learning to be able to train the model at scale, so you can analyze the packages in batches.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Train an AutoML model on your corpus of images, and build an API around that model to integrate with the package tracking applications. </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the Cloud Vision API to detect for damage, and raise an alert through Cloud Function. Integrate the package tracking applications with this function.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use TensorFlow to create a model that is trained on your corpus of image. Create a Python notebook in Cloud Datalab that uses this model so you can analyze for damaged packages.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are migrating your data warehouse to BigQuery. You have migrated all of your data into tables in a dataset. Multiple users from your organization will be using the data. They should only see certain tables based on their team membership. How should you set user permissions?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Assign the users/groups data viewer access at the table level for each table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create SQL views for each team in the same dataset in which the data resides, and assign the users/groups data viewer access to the SQL views.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create authorized views for each team in the same dataset in which the data resides, and assign the users/groups data viewer access to the authorized views.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create authorized views for each team in datasets created for each team. Assign the authorized views data viewer access to the dataset in which the data reside. Assign the users/groups data viewer access to the datasets in which the authorized views reside.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building a new data pipeline to share data between two different types of applications: jobs generators and job runners. Your solution must scale to accommodate increases in usage and must accommodate the addition of new applications without negatively affecting the performance of existing ones. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an API using App Engine to receive and send messages to the applications </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use a Cloud Pub/Sub topic to publish jobs, and use subscriptions to execute them </detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table on Cloud SQL, and insert and delete rows with the job information</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table on Cloud Spanner, and insert and delete rows with the job information</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building a data pipeline on Google Cloud. You need to prepare data using a casual method for a machine-learning process. You want to support a logistic regression model. You also need to monitor and adjust for null values, which must remain real-valued and cannot be removed. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataprep to find null values in sample source data, Convert all nulls to ‘none’ using a Cloud Dataproc job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataprep to find null values in sample source data, Convert all nulls to 0 using a Cloud Dataprep job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow to find null values in sample source data, Convert all nulls to ‘none’ using a Cloud Dataprep job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow to find null values in sample source data, Convert all nulls to using a custom script.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company produces 20,000 files every hour. Each data file is formatted as a comma separated values (CSV) file that is less than 4 KB. All files must be ingested on Google Cloud Platform before they can be processed. Your company site has a 200 ms latency to Google Cloud, and your Internet connection bandwidth is limited as 50 Mbps. You currently deploy a secure FTP (SFTP) server on a virtual machine in Google Compute Engine as the data ingestion point. A local SFTP client runs on a dedicated machine to transmit the CSV files as is. The goal is to make reports with data from the previous day available to the executives by 10:00 a.m. each day. This design is barely able to keep up with the current volume, even though the bandwidth utilization is rather low. You are told that due to seasonality, your company expects the number of files to double for the next three months. Which two actions should you take? (choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Introduce data compression for each file to increase the rate file of file transfer.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Contact your internet service provider (ISP) to increase your maximum bandwidth to at least 100 Mbps.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Redesign the data ingestion process to use gsutil tool to send the CSV files to a storage bucket in parallel.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Assemble 1,000 files into a tape archive (TAR) file. Transmit the TAR files instead, and disassemble the CSV files in the cloud upon receiving them.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an S3-compatible storage endpoint in your network, and use Google Cloud Storage Transfer Service to transfer on-premices data to the designated storage bucket.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your startup has never implemented a formal security policy. Currently, everyone in the company has access to the datasets stored in Google BigQuery. Teams have freedom to use the service as they see fit, and they have not documented their use cases. You have been asked to secure the data warehouse. You need to discover what everyone is doing. What should you do first?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Google Stackdriver Audit Logs to review data access.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Get the identity and access management IIAM) policy of each table</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Stackdriver Monitoring to see the usage of BigQuery query slots.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the Google Cloud Billing API to see what account the warehouse is being billed to.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to process payment transactions in a point-of-sale application that will run on Google Cloud Platform. Your user base could grow exponentially, but you do not want to manage infrastructure scaling. Which Google database service should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are working on a sensitive project involving private user data. You have set up a project on Google Cloud Platform to house your work internally. An external consultant is going to assist with coding a complex transformation in a Google Cloud Dataflow pipeline for your project. How should you maintain users’ privacy?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Grant the consultant the Viewer role on the project.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Grant the consultant the Cloud Dataflow Developer role on the project.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a service account and allow the consultant to log on with it.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create an anonymized sample of the data for the consultant to work with in a different project.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company built a TensorFlow neutral-network model with a large number of neurons and layers. The model fits well for the training data. However, when tested against new data, it performs poorly. What method can you employ to address this?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Threading</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Serialization</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Dropout Methods</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dimensionality Reduction</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is loading comma-separated values (CSV) files into Google BigQuery. The data is fully imported successfully; however, the imported data is not matching byte-to-byte to the source file. What is the most likely cause of this problem?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The CSV data loaded in BigQuery is not flagged as CSV.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The CSV data has invalid rows that were skipped on import.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>The CSV data loaded in BigQuery is not using BigQuery’s default encoding.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The CSV data has not gone through an ETL phase before loading into BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these are examples of a value in a sparse vector? (Select 2 answers.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>[0, 5, 0, 0, 0, 0]</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>[0, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0, 1]</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>[0, 1]</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>[1, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0]</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these sources can you not load data into BigQuery from?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>File upload</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Google Drive</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Google Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Google Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>When you store data in Cloud Bigtable, what is the recommended minimum amount of stored data?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>500 TB</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>1 GB</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>1 TB</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>500 GB</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
   </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following IAM roles does your Compute Engine account require to be able to run pipeline jobs?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>dataflow.worker</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>dataflow.compute</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>dataflow.developer</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>dataflow.viewer</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following statements about the Wide and Deep Learning model are true? (Select 2 answers.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>The wide model is used for memorization, while the deep model is used for generalization.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>A good use for the wide and deep model is a recommender system.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The wide model is used for generalization, while the deep model is used for memorization.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>A good use for the wide and deep model is a small-scale linear regression problem.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>When creating a new Cloud Dataproc cluster with the projects.regions.clusters.create operation, these four values are required: project, region, name, and _____.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>zone</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>node</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>label</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>type</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which Cloud Dataflow / Beam feature should you use to aggregate data in an unbounded data source every hour based on the time when the data entered the pipeline?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An hourly watermark</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An event time trigger</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The with Allowed Lateness method</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>A processing time trigger</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which SQL keyword can be used to reduce the number of columns processed by BigQuery?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BETWEEN</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>WHERE</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>SELECT</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>LIMIT</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your team is responsible for developing and maintaining ETLs in your company. One of your Dataflow jobs is failing because of some errors in the input data, and you need to improve reliability of the pipeline (incl. being able to reprocess all failing data). What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a filtering step to skip these types of errors in the future, extract erroneous rows from logs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a try... catch block to your DoFn that transforms the data, extract erroneous rows from logs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a try... catch block to your DoFn that transforms the data, write erroneous rows to PubSub directly from the DoFn.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Add a try... catch block to your DoFn that transforms the data, use a sideOutput to create a PCollection that can be stored to PubSub later.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company maintains a hybrid deployment with GCP, where analytics are performed on your anonymized customer data. The data are imported to Cloud Storage from your data center through parallel uploads to a data transfer server running on GCP. Management informs you that the daily transfers take too long and have asked you to fix the problem. You want to maximize transfer speeds. Which action should you take?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the CPU size on your server.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the size of the Google Persistent Disk on your server.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Increase your network bandwidth from your datacenter to GCP.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase your network bandwidth from Compute Engine to Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have some data, which is shown in the graphic below. The two dimensions are X and Y, and the shade of each dot represents what class it is. You want to classify this data accurately using a linear algorithm. To do this you need to add a synthetic feature. What should the value of that feature be?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>X^2+Y^2</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>X^2</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Y^2</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>cos(X)</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company has a hybrid cloud initiative. You have a complex data pipeline that moves data between cloud provider services and leverages services from each of the cloud providers. Which cloud-native service should you use to orchestrate the entire pipeline?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataflow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Composer</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataprep</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataproc</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>After migrating ETL jobs to run on BigQuery, you need to verify that the output of the migrated jobs is the same as the output of the original. You’ve loaded a table containing the output of the original job and want to compare the contents with output from the migrated job to show that they are identical. The tables do not contain a primary key column that would enable you to join them together for comparison. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Select random samples from the tables using the RAND() function and compare the samples.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Select random samples from the tables using the HASH() function and compare the samples.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use a Dataproc cluster and the BigQuery Hadoop connector to read the data from each table and calculate a hash from non-timestamp columns of the table after sorting. Compare the hashes of each table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create stratified random samples using the OVER() function and compare equivalent samples from each table.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You use a dataset in BigQuery for analysis. You want to provide third-party companies with access to the same dataset. You need to keep the costs of data sharing low and ensure that the data is current. Which solution should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create an authorized view on the BigQuery table to control data access, and provide third-party companies with access to that view.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Scheduler to export the data on a regular basis to Cloud Storage, and provide third-party companies with access to the bucket.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a separate dataset in BigQuery that contains the relevant data to share, and provide third-party companies with access to the new dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud Dataflow job that reads the data in frequent time intervals, and writes it to the relevant BigQuery dataset or Cloud Storage bucket for third-party companies to use.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You operate a database that stores stock trades and an application that retrieves average stock price for a given company over an adjustable window of time. The data is stored in Cloud Bigtable where the datetime of the stock trade is the beginning of the row key. Your application has thousands of concurrent users, and you notice that performance is starting to degrade as more stocks are added. What should you do to improve the performance of your application?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Change the row key syntax in your Cloud Bigtable table to begin with the stock symbol.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Change the row key syntax in your Cloud Bigtable table to begin with a random number per second.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Change the data pipeline to use BigQuery for storing stock trades, and update your application.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow to write summary of each day’s stock trades to an Avro file on Cloud Storage.Update your application to read from Cloud Storage and Cloud Bigtable to compute the responses.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Each analytics team in your organization is running BigQuery jobs in their own projects. You want to enable each team to monitor slot usage within their projects. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Stackdriver Monitoring dashboard based on the BigQuery metric query/scanned_bytes</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a Stackdriver Monitoring dashboard based on the BigQuery metric slots/allocated_for_project</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a log export for each project, capture the BigQuery job execution logs, create a custom metric based on the totalSlotMs, and create a Stackdriver Monitoring dashboard based on the custom metric</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an aggregated log export at the organization level, capture the BigQuery job execution logs, create a custom metric based on the totalSlotMs, and create a Stackdriver Monitoring dashboard based on the custom metric </detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to create a new transaction table in Cloud Spanner that stores product sales data. You are deciding what to use as a primary key. From a performance perspective, which strategy should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The current epoch time</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>A concatenation of the product name and the current epoch time</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>A random universally unique identifier number (version 4 UUID)</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The original order identification number from the sales system, which is a monotonically increasing integer</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Data Analysts in your company have the Cloud IAM Owner role assigned to them in their projects to allow them to work with multiple GCP products in their projects. Your organization requires that all BigQuery data access logs be retained for 6 months. You need to ensure that only audit personnel in your company can access the data access logs for all projects. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Enable data access logs in each Data Analyst’s project. Restrict access to Stackdriver Logging via Cloud IAM roles.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the data access logs via a project-level export sink to a Cloud Storage bucket in the Data Analysts’ project. Restrict access to the Cloud Storage bucket.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the data access logs via a project-level export sink to a Cloud Storage bucket in a newly created projects for audit log. Restrict access to the project with the exported logs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Export the data access logs via an aggregated export sink to a Cloud Storage bucket in a newly created project for audit log. Restrict access to the project that contains the exported logs.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company receives both batch- and stream-based event data. You want to process the data using Google Cloud Dataflow over a predictable time period. However, you realize that in some instances data can arrive late or out of order. How should you design your Cloud Dataflow pipeline to handle data that is late or out of order?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set a single global window to capture all the data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Set sliding windows to capture all the lagged data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use watermarks and timestamps to capture the lagged data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Ensure every datasource type (stream or batch) has a timestamp, and use the timestamps to define the logic for lagged data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to create a near real-time inventory dashboard that reads the main inventory tables in your BigQuery data warehouse. Historical inventory data is stored as inventory balances by item and location. You have several thousand updates to inventory every hour. You want to maximize performance of the dashboard and ensure that the data is accurate. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Leverage BigQuery UPDATE statements to update the inventory balances as they are changing.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Partition the inventory balance table by item to reduce the amount of data scanned with each inventory update.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use the BigQuery streaming the stream changes into a daily inventory movement table. Calculate balances in a view that joins it to the historical inventory balance table. Update the inventory balance table nightly.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the BigQuery bulk loader to batch load inventory changes into a daily inventory movement table.Calculate balances in a view that joins it to the historical inventory balance table. Update the inventory balance table nightly.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are implementing several batch jobs that must be executed on a schedule. These jobs have many interdependent steps that must be executed in a specific order. Portions of the jobs involve executing shell scripts, running Hadoop jobs, and running queries in BigQuery. The jobs are expected to run for many minutes up to several hours. If the steps fail, they must be retried a fixed number of times. Which service should you use to manage the execution of these jobs?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Scheduler</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataflow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Functions</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Composer</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have a data stored in BigQuery. The data in the BigQuery dataset must be highly available. You need to define a storage, backup, and recovery strategy of this data that minimizes cost. How should you configure the BigQuery table?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set the BigQuery dataset to be regional. In the event of an emergency, use a point-in-time snapshot to recover the data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set the BigQuery dataset to be regional. Create a scheduled query to make copies of the data to tables suffixed with the time of the backu E. In the event of an emergency, use the backup copy of the table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Set the BigQuery dataset to be multi-regional. In the event of an emergency, use a point-in-time snapshot to recover the data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set the BigQuery dataset to be multi-regional. Create a scheduled query to make copies of the data to tables suffixed with the time of the backup. In the event of an emergency, use the backup copy of the table.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have an Apache Kafka Cluster on-prem with topics containing web application logs. You need to replicate the data to Google Cloud for analysis in BigQuery and Cloud Storage. The preferred replication method is mirroring to avoid deployment of Kafka Connect plugins. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Deploy a Kafka cluster on GCE VM Instances. Configure your on-prem cluster to mirror your topics to the cluster running in GCE. Use a Dataproc cluster or Dataflow job to read from Kafka and write to GCS.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy a Kafka cluster on GCE VM Instances with the Pub/Sub Kafka connector configured as a Sink connector. Use a Dataproc cluster or Dataflow job to read from Kafka and write to GCS.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy the Pub/Sub Kafka connector to your on-prem Kafka cluster and configure Pub/Sub as a Source connector. Use a Dataflow job to read from Pub/Sub and write to GCS.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy the Pub/Sub Kafka connector to your on-prem Kafka cluster and configure Pub/Sub as a Sink connector. Use a Dataflow job to read from Pub/Sub and write to GCS.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>A data scientist has created a BigQuery ML model and asks you to create an ML pipeline to serve predictions. You have a REST API application with the requirement to serve predictions for an individual user ID with latency under 100 milliseconds. You use the following query to generate predictions: SELECT predicted_label, user_id FROM ML.PREDICT (MODEL ‘dataset.model’, table user_features). How should you create the ML pipeline?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a WHERE clause to the query, and grant the BigQuery Data Viewer role to the application service account.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an Authorized View with the provided query. Share the dataset that contains the view with the application service account.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud Dataflow pipeline using BigQueryIO to read results from the query. Grant the Dataflow Worker role to the application service account.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud Dataflow pipeline using BigQueryIO to read predictions for all users from the query. Write the results to Cloud Bigtable using BigtableIO. Grant the Bigtable Reader role to the application service account so that the application can read predictions for individual users from Cloud Bigtable.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your software uses a simple JSON format for all messages. These messages are published to Google Cloud Pub/Sub, then processed with Google Cloud Dataflow to create a real-time dashboard for the CFO. During testing, you notice that some messages are missing in the dashboard. You check the logs, and all messages are being published to Cloud Pub/Sub successfully. What should you do next?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Check the dashboard application to see if it is not displaying correctly.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Run a fixed dataset through the Cloud Dataflow pipeline and analyze the output.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Google Stackdriver Monitoring on Cloud Pub/Sub to find the missing messages.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Switch Cloud Dataflow to pull messages from Cloud Pub/Sub instead of Cloud Pub/Sub pushing messages to Cloud Dataflow.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to use Google Stackdriver Logging to monitor Google BigQuery usage. You need an instant notification to be sent to your monitoring tool when new data is appended to a certain table using an insert job, but you do not want to receive notifications for other tables. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Make a call to the Stackdriver API to list all logs, and apply an advanced filter.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>In the Stackdriver logging admin interface, and enable a log sink export to BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>In the Stackdriver logging admin interface, enable a log sink export to Google Cloud Pub/Sub, and subscribe to the topic from your monitoring tool.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Using the Stackdriver API, create a project sink with advanced log filter to export to Pub/Sub, and subscribe to the topic from your monitoring tool.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is in a highly regulated industry. One of your requirements is to ensure individual users have access only to the minimum amount of information required to do their jobs. You want to enforce this requirement with Google BigQuery. Which three approaches can you take? (Choose three.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Disable writes to certain tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Restrict access to tables by role.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Ensure that the data is encrypted at all times.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Restrict BigQuery API access to approved users.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Segregate data across multiple tables or databases.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Google Stackdriver Audit Logging to determine policy violations.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company’s customer and order databases are often under heavy load. This makes performing analytics against them difficult without harming operations. The databases are in a MySQL cluster, with nightly backups taken using mysqldump. You want to perform analytics with minimal impact on operations. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a node to the MySQL cluster and build an OLAP cube there.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use an ETL tool to load the data from MySQL into Google BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Connect an on-premises Apache Hadoop cluster to MySQL and perform ETL.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Mount the backups to Google Cloud SQL, and then process the data using Google Cloud Dataproc.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company has hired a new data scientist who wants to perform complicated analyses across very large datasets stored in Google Cloud Storage and in a Cassandra cluster on Google Compute Engine. The scientist primarily wants to create labelled data sets for machine learning projects, along with some visualization tasks. She reports that her laptop is not powerful enough to perform her tasks and it is slowing her down. You want to help her perform her tasks. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Run a local version of Jupiter on the laptop.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Grant the user access to Google Cloud Shell.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Host a visualization tool on a VM on Google Compute Engine.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Deploy Google Cloud Datalab to a virtual machine (VM) on Google Compute Engine.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building a model to make clothing recommendations. You know a user’s fashion preference is likely to change over time, so you build a data pipeline to stream new data back to the model as it becomes available. How should you use this data to train the model?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Continuously retrain the model on just the new data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Continuously retrain the model on a combination of existing data and the new data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Train on the existing data while using the new data as your test set.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Train on the new data while using the existing data as your test set.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building a model to predict whether or not it will rain on a given day. You have thousands of input features and want to see if you can improve training speed by removing some features while having a minimum effect on model accuracy. What can you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Eliminate features that are highly correlated to the output labels.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Combine highly co-dependent features into one representative feature.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Instead of feeding in each feature individually, average their values in batches of 3.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Remove the features that have null values for more than 50% of the training records.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Flowlogistic’s CEO wants to gain rapid insight into their customer base so his sales team can be better informed in the field. This team is not very technical, so they’ve purchased a visualization tool to simplify the creation of BigQuery reports. However, they’ve been overwhelmed by all the data in the table, and are spending a lot of money on queries trying to find the data they need. You want to solve their problem in the most cost-effective way. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the data into a Google Sheet for virtualization.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an additional table with only the necessary columns.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a view on the table to present to the virtualization tool.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create identity and access management (IAM) roles on the appropriate columns, so only they appear in a query.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to compose visualization for operations teams with the following requirements:
- Telemetry must include data from all 50,000 installations for the most recent 6 weeks (sampling once every minute)
- The report must not be more than 3 hours delayed from live data.
- The actionable report should only show suboptimal links.
- Most suboptimal links should be sorted to the top.
- Suboptimal links can be grouped and filtered by regional geography.
- User response time to load the report must be less than 5 seconds.

You create a data source to store the last 6 weeks of data, and create visualizations that allow viewers to see multiple date ranges, distinct geographic regions, and unique installation types. You always show the latest data without any changes to your visualizations. You want to avoid creating and updating new visualizations each month. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Look through the current data and compose a series of charts and tables, one for each possible combination of criteria.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Look through the current data and compose a small set of generalized charts and tables bound to criteria filters that allow value selection.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the data to a spreadsheet, compose a series of charts and tables, one for each possible combination of criteria, and spread them across multiple tabs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the data into relational database tables, write a Google App Engine application that queries all rows, summarizes the data across each criteria, and then renders results using the Google Charts and visualization API.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company has recently grown rapidly and now ingesting data at a significantly higher rate than it was previously. You manage the daily batch MapReduce analytics jobs in Apache Hadoop. However, the recent increase in data has meant the batch jobs are falling behind. You were asked to recommend ways the development team could increase the responsiveness of the analytics without increasing costs. What should you recommend they do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Rewrite the job in Pig.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rewrite the job in Apache Spark.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the size of the Hadoop cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Decrease the size of the Hadoop cluster but also rewrite the job in Hive.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a manufacturing plant that batches application log files together into a single log file once a day at 2:00 AM. You have written a Google Cloud Dataflow job to process that log file. You need to make sure the log file in processed once per day as inexpensively as possible. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Change the processing job to use Google Cloud Dataproc instead.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Manually start the Cloud Dataflow job each morning when you get into the office.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a cron job with Google App Engine Cron Service to run the Cloud Dataflow job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Configure the Cloud Dataflow job as a streaming job so that it processes the log data immediately.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which TensorFlow function can you use to configure a categorical column if you don't know all of the possible values for that column?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>categorical_column_with_vocabulary_list</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>categorical_column_with_hash_bucket</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>categorical_column_with_unknown_values</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>sparse_column_with_keys</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What is the HBase Shell for Cloud Bigtable?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a GUI based interface that performs administrative tasks, such as creating and deleting tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a command-line tool that performs administrative tasks, such as creating and deleting tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a hypervisor based shell that performs administrative tasks, such as creating and deleting new</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a command-line tool that performs only user account management functions to grant access to</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Dataproc clusters contain many configuration files. To update these files, you will need to use the --properties option. file_prefix:property= .</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>details</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>value</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>null</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>id</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these rules apply when you add preemptible workers to a Dataproc cluster (select 2 answers)?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Preemptible workers cannot use persistent disk.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Preemptible workers cannot store data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>If a preemptible worker is reclaimed, then a replacement worker must be added manually.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>A Dataproc cluster cannot have only preemptible workers.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How can you get a neural network to learn about relationships between categories in a categorical feature?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a multi-hot column</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a one-hot column</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a hash bucket</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create an embedding column</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following is not true about Dataflow pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines are a set of operations</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines represent a data processing job</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines represent a directed graph of steps</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines can share data between instances</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What are the minimum permissions needed for a service account used with Google Dataproc?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Execute to Google Cloud Storage; write to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write to Google Cloud Storage; read to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Execute to Google Cloud Storage; execute to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Read and write to Google Cloud Storage; write to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following is NOT true about Dataflow pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines are tied to Dataflow, and cannot be run on any other runner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines can consume data from other Google Cloud services</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines can be programmed in Java</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines use a unified programming model, so can work both with streaming and batch data sources</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which software libraries are supported by Cloud Machine Learning Engine?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Theano and TensorFlow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Theano and Torch</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>TensorFlow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>TensorFlow and Torch</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a mid-sized enterprise that needs to move its operational system transaction data from an on-premises database to GCP. The database is about 20 TB in size. Which database should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Spanner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company needs to upload their historic data to Cloud Storage. The security rules don’t allow access from external IPs to their on-premises resources. After an initial upload, they will add new data from existing on-premises applications every day. What should they do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Execute gsutil rsync from the on-premises servers.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow and write the data to Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write a job template in Cloud Dataproc to perform the data transfer.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install an FTP server on a Compute Engine VM to receive the files and move them to Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing a data processing pipeline. The pipeline must be able to scale automatically as load increases. Messages must be processed at least once, and must be ordered within windows of 1 hour. How should you design the solution?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Apache Kafka for message ingestion and use Cloud Dataproc for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Apache Kafka for message ingestion and use Cloud Dataflow for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Pub/Sub for message ingestion and Cloud Dataproc for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Pub/Sub for message ingestion and Cloud Dataflow for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are operating a streaming Cloud Dataflow pipeline. Your engineers have a new version of the pipeline with a different windowing algorithm and triggering strategy. You want to update the running pipeline with the new version. You want to ensure that no data is lost during the update. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Update the Cloud Dataflow pipeline inflight by passing the --update option with the --jobName set to the existing job name</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Update the Cloud Dataflow pipeline inflight by passing the --update option with the --jobName set to a new unique job name</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Stop the Cloud Dataflow pipeline with the Cancel option. Create a new Cloud Dataflow job with the updated code.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Stop the Cloud Dataflow pipeline with the Drain option. Create a new Cloud Dataflow job with the updated code.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are responsible for writing your company’s ETL pipelines to run on an Apache Hadoop cluster. The pipeline will require some checkpointing and splitting pipelines. Which method should you use to write the pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>PigLatin using Pig</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>HiveQL using Hive</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Java using MapReduce</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Python using MapReduce</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to create a data pipeline that copies time-series transaction data so that it can be queried from within BigQuery by your data science team for analysis. Every hour, thousands of transactions are updated with a new status. The size of the intitial dataset is 1.5 PB, and it will grow by 3 TB per day. The data is heavily structured, and your data science team will build machine learning models based on this data. You want to maximize performance and usability for your data science team. Which two strategies should you adopt? Choose 2 answers.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Denormalize the data as must as possible.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Preserve the structure of the data as much as possible.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery UPDATE to further reduce the size of the dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Develop a data pipeline where status updates are appended to BigQuery instead of updated.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Copy a daily snapshot of transaction data to Cloud Storage and store it as an Avro file. Use BigQuery’ssupport for external data sources to query.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are operating a Cloud Dataflow streaming pipeline. The pipeline aggregates events from a Cloud Pub/Sub subscription source, within a window, and sinks the resulting aggregation to a Cloud Storage bucket. The source has consistent throughput. You want to monitor an alert on behavior of the pipeline with Cloud Stackdriver to ensure that it is processing data. Which Stackdriver alerts should you create?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on a decrease of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the source and a rate of change increase of instance/storage/used_bytes for the destination</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on an increase of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the source and a rate of change decrease of instance/storage/used_bytes for the destination</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on a decrease of instance/storage/used_bytes for the source and a rate of change increase of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the destination</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on an increase of instance/storage/used_bytes for the source and a rate of change decrease of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the destination</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You architect a system to analyze seismic data. Your extract, transform, and load (ETL) process runs as a series of MapReduce jobs on an Apache Hadoop cluster. The ETL process takes days to process a data set because some steps are computationally expensive. Then you discover that a sensor calibration step has been omitted. How should you change your ETL process to carry out sensor calibration systematically in the future?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Modify the transformMapReduce jobs to apply sensor calibration before they do anything else.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Introduce a new MapReduce job to apply sensor calibration to raw data, and ensure all other MapReduce jobs are chained after this.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add sensor calibration data to the output of the ETL process, and document that all users need to apply sensor calibration themselves.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Develop an algorithm through simulation to predict variance of data output from the last MapReduce job based on calibration factors, and apply the correction to all data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You’re using Bigtable for a real-time application, and you have a heavy load that is a mix of read and writes. You’ve recently identified an additional use case and need to perform hourly an analytical job to calculate certain statistics across the whole database. You need to ensure both the reliability of your production application as well as the analytical workload. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export Bigtable dump to GCS and run your analytical job on top of the exported files.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Add a second cluster to an existing instance with a multi-cluster routing, use live-traffic app profile for your regular workload and batch-analytics profile for the analytics workload.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a second cluster to an existing instance with a single-cluster routing, use live-traffic app profile for your regular workload and batch-analytics profile for the analytics workload.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the size of your existing cluster twice and execute your analytics workload on your new resized cluster.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to archive data in Cloud Storage. Because some data is very sensitive, you want to use the “Trust No One” (TNO) approach to encrypt your data to prevent the cloud provider staff from decrypting your data. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gcloud kms keys create to create a symmetric key. Then use gcloud kms encrypt to encrypt each archival file with the key and unique additional authenticated data (AAD). Use gsutil cp to upload each encrypted file to the Cloud Storage bucket, and keep the AAD outside of Google Cloud.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use gcloud kms keys create to create a symmetric key. Then use gcloud kms encrypt to encrypt each archival file with the key. Use gsutil cp to upload each encrypted file to the Cloud Storage bucket. Manually destroy the key previously used for encryption, and rotate the key once.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Specify customer-supplied encryption key (CSEK) in the .boto configuration file. Use gsutil cp to upload each archival file to the Cloud Storage bucket. Save the CSEK in Cloud Memorystore as permanent storage of the secret.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Specify customer-supplied encryption key (CSEK) in the .boto configuration file. Use gsutil cp to upload each archival file to the Cloud Storage bucket. Save the CSEK in a different project that only the security team can access.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to use a database of information about tissue samples to classify future tissue samples as either normal or mutated. You are evaluating an unsupervised anomaly detection method for classifying the tissue samples. Which two characteristic support this method? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>There are very few occurrences of mutations relative to normal samples.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>There are roughly equal occurrences of both normal and mutated samples in the database.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>You expect future mutations to have different features from the mutated samples in the database.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You expect future mutations to have similar features to the mutated samples in the database.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You already have labels for which samples are mutated and which are normal in the database.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is running their first dynamic campaign, serving different offers by analyzing real-time data during the holiday season. The data scientists are collecting terabytes of data that rapidly grows every hour during their 30-day campaign. They are using Google Cloud Dataflow to preprocess the data and collect the feature (signals) data that is needed for the machine learning model in Google Cloud Bigtable. The team is observing suboptimal performance with reads and writes of their initial load of 10 TB of data. They want to improve this performance while minimizing cost. What should they do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Redefine the schema by evenly distributing reads and writes across the row space of the table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The performance issue should be resolved over time as the site of the BigDate cluster is increased.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Redesign the schema to use a single row key to identify values that need to be updated frequently in the cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Redesign the schema to use row keys based on numeric IDs that increase sequentially per user viewing the offers.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Flowlogistic's management has determined that the current Apache Kafka servers cannot handle the data volume for their real-time inventory tracking system. You need to build a new system on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) that will feed the proprietary tracking software. The system must be able to ingest data from a variety of global sources, process and query in real-time, and store the data reliably. Which combination of GCP products should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Pub/Sub, Cloud Dataflow, and Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Pub/Sub, Cloud Dataflow, and Local SSD</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Pub/Sub, Cloud SQL, and Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Load Balancing, Cloud Dataflow, and Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Dataflow, Cloud SQL, and Cloud Storage</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You create a new report for your large team in Google Data Studio 360. The report uses Google BigQuery as its data source. It is company policy to ensure employees can view only the data associated with their region, so you create and populate a table for each region. You need to enforce the regional access policy to the data. Which two actions should you take? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Ensure all the tables are included in global dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Ensure each table is included in a dataset for a region.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Adjust the settings for each table to allow a related region-based security group view access.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Adjust the settings for each view to allow a related region-based security group view access.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Adjust the settings for each dataset to allow a related region-based security group view access.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>All Google Cloud Bigtable client requests go through a front-end server they are sent to a Cloud Bigtable node.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>before</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>after</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>only if</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>once</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these is NOT a way to customize the software on Dataproc cluster instances?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set initialization actions</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Modify configuration files using cluster properties</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Configure the cluster using Cloud Deployment Manager</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Log into the master node and make changes from there</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these operations can you perform from the BigQuery Web UI?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Upload a file in SQL format.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Load data with nested and repeated fields.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Upload a 20 MB file.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Upload multiple files using a wildcard.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What are two methods that can be used to denormalize tables in BigQuery?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Split table into multiple tables; Use a partitioned table</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Join tables into one table; Use nested repeated fields</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a partitioned table; Join tables into one table</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use nested repeated fields; Use a partitioned table</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which role must be assigned to a service account used by the virtual machines in a Dataproc cluster so they can execute jobs?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Dataproc Worker</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataproc Viewer</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataproc Runner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataproc Editor</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which Java SDK class can you use to run your Dataflow programs locally?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>LocalRunner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>DirectPipelineRunner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>MachineRunner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>LocalPipelineRunner</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which is not a valid reason for poor Cloud Bigtable performance?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The workload isn't appropriate for Cloud Bigtable.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The table's schema is not designed correctly.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>The Cloud Bigtable cluster has too many nodes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>There are issues with the network connection.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Scaling a Cloud Dataproc cluster typically involves _____.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>increasing or decreasing the number of worker nodes</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>increasing or decreasing the number of master nodes</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>moving memory to run more applications on a single node</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>deleting applications from unused nodes periodically</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>To give a user read permission for only the first three columns of a table, which access control method would you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Primitive role</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Predefined role</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Authorized view</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>It's not possible to give access to only the first three columns of a table.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to use a BigQuery table as a data sink. In which writing mode(s) can you use BigQuery as a sink?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Both batch and streaming</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery cannot be used as a sink</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Only batch</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Only streaming</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Cloud Dataproc is a managed Apache Hadoop and Apache service.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Blaze</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Spark</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Fire</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Ignite</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which action can a Cloud Dataproc Viewer perform?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Submit a job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Delete a cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>List the jobs.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are running a pipeline in Cloud Dataflow that receives messages from a Cloud Pub/Sub topic and writes the results to a BigQuery dataset in the EU. Currently, your pipeline is located in europe-west4 and has a maximum of 3 workers, instance type n1-standard-1. You notice that during peak periods, your pipeline is struggling to process records in a timely fashion, when all 3 workers are at maximum CPU utilization. Which two actions can you take to increase performance of your pipeline? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Increase the number of max workers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use a larger instance type for your Cloud Dataflow workers</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Change the zone of your Cloud Dataflow pipeline to run in us-central1</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a temporary table in Cloud Bigtable that will act as a buffer for new data. Create a new step in your pipeline to write to this table first, and then create a new pipeline to write from Cloud Bigtable to BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>A shipping company has live package-tracking data that is sent to an Apache Kafka stream in real time. This is then loaded into BigQuery. Analysts in your company want to query the tracking data in BigQuery to analyze geospatial trends in the lifecycle of a package. The table was originally created with ingest-date partitioning. Over time, the query processing time has increased. You need to implement a change that would improve query performance in BigQuery. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Implement clustering in BigQuery on the ingest date column.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Implement clustering in BigQuery on the package-tracking ID column.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Tier older data onto Cloud Storage files, and leverage extended tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Re-create the table using data partitioning on the package delivery date.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
   </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have a requirement to insert minute-resolution data from 50,000 sensors into a BigQuery table. You expect significant growth in data volume and need the data to be available within 1 minute of ingestion for real-time analysis of aggregated trends. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use bq load to load a batch of sensor data every 60 seconds.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use a Cloud Dataflow pipeline to stream data into the BigQuery table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the INSERT statement to insert a batch of data every 60 seconds.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the MERGE statement to apply updates in batch every 60 seconds.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You’re training a model to predict housing prices based on an available dataset with real estate properties. Your plan is to train a fully connected neural net, and you’ve discovered that the dataset contains latitude and longtitude of the property. Real estate professionals have told you that the location of the property is highly influential on price, so you’d like to engineer a feature that incorporates this physical dependency. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Provide latitude and longtitude as input vectors to your neural net.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a numeric column from a feature cross of latitude and longtitude.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a feature cross of latitude and longtitude, bucketize at the minute level and use L1 regularization during optimization.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a feature cross of latitude and longtitude, bucketize it at the minute level and use L2 regularization during optimization.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing storage for two relational tables that are part of a 10-TB database on Google Cloud. You want to support transactions that scale horizontally. You also want to optimize data for range queries on nonkey columns. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud SQL for storage. Add secondary indexes to support query patterns.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud SQL for storage. Use Cloud Dataflow to transform data to support query patterns.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Spanner for storage. Add secondary indexes to support query patterns.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Spanner for storage. Use Cloud Dataflow to transform data to support query patterns.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have a data pipeline that writes data to Cloud Bigtable using well-designed row keys. You want to monitor your pipeline to determine when to increase the size of you Cloud Bigtable cluster. Which two actions can you take to accomplish this? Choose 2 answers.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Review Key Visualizer metric. Increase the size of the Cloud Bigtable cluster when the Read pressure index is above 100.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Review Key Visualizer metric. Increase the size of the Cloud Bigtable cluster when the Write pressure index is above 100.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Monitor the latency of write operation. Increase the size of the Cloud Bigtable cluster when there is a sustained increase in write latency.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Monitor storage utilization. Increase the size of the Cloud Bigtable cluster when utilization increases above 70% of max capacity.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Monitor latency of read operation. Increase the size of the Cloud Bigtable cluster of read operations take longer than 100 ms.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Government regulations in your industry mandate that you have to maintain an auditable record of access to certain types of datA. Assuming that all expiring logs will be archived correctly, where should you store data that is subject to that mandate?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Encrypted on Cloud Storage with user-supplied encryption keys. A separate decryption key will be given to each authorized user.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>In a BigQuery dataset that is viewable only by authorized personnel, with the Data Access log used to provide the auditability.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>In Cloud SQL, with separate database user names to each user. The Cloud SQL Admin activity logs will be used to provide the auditability.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>In a bucket on Cloud Storage that is accessible only by an AppEngine service that collects user information and logs the access before providing a link to the bucket.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have a query that filters a BigQuery table using a WHERE clause on timestamp and ID columns. By using bq query – -dry_run you learn that the query triggers a full scan of the table, even though the filter on timestamp and ID select a tiny fraction of the overall data. You want to reduce the amount of data scanned by BigQuery with minimal changes to existing SQL queries. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a separate table for each ID.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use the LIMIT keyword to reduce the number of rows returned.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Recreate the table with a partitioning column and clustering column.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use the bq query - -maximum_bytes_billed flag to restrict the number of bytes billed.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are planning to migrate your current on-premises Apache Hadoop deployment to the cloud. You need to ensure that the deployment is as fault-tolerant and cost-effective as possible for long-running batch jobs. You want to use a managed service. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Deploy a Cloud Dataproc cluster. Use a standard persistent disk and 50% preemptible workers. Store data in Cloud Storage, and change references in scripts from hdfs:// to gs://</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy a Cloud Dataproc cluster. Use an SSD persistent disk and 50% preemptible workers. Store data in Cloud Storage, and change references in scripts from hdfs:// to gs://</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install Hadoop and Spark on a 10-node Compute Engine instance group with standard instances. Install the Cloud Storage connector, and store the data in Cloud Storage. Change references in scripts from hdfs:// to gs://</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install Hadoop and Spark on a 10-node Compute Engine instance group with preemptible instances. Store data in HDFS. Change references in scripts from hdfs:// to gs://</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have a petabyte of analytics data and need to design a storage and processing platform for it. You must be able to perform data warehouse-style analytics on the data in Google Cloud and expose the dataset as files for batch analysis tools in other cloud providers. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store and process the entire dataset in BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store and process the entire dataset in Cloud Bigtable.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store the full dataset in BigQuery, and store a compressed copy of the data in a Cloud Storage bucket.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Store the warm data as files in Cloud Storage, and store the active data in BigQuery. Keep this ratio as 80% warm and 20% active.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You store historic data in Cloud Storage. You need to perform analytics on the historic data. You want to use a solution to detect invalid data entries and perform data transformations that will not require programming or knowledge of SQL. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow with Beam to detect errors and perform transformations.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataprep with recipes to detect errors and perform transformations.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataproc with a Hadoop job to detect errors and perform transformations.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use federated tables in BigQuery with queries to detect errors and perform transformations.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to use a database of information about tissue samples to classify future tissue samples as either normal or mutated. You are evaluating an unsupervised anomaly detection method for classifying the tissue samples. Which two characteristic support this method? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>There are very few occurrences of mutations relative to normal samples.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>There are roughly equal occurrences of both normal and mutated samples in the database.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>You expect future mutations to have different features from the mutated samples in the database.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You expect future mutations to have similar features to the mutated samples in the database.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>You already have labels for which samples are mutated and which are normal in the database.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have spent a few days loading data from comma-separated values (CSV) files into the Google BigQuery table CLICK_STREAM. The column DT stores the epoch time of click events. For convenience, you chose a simple schema where every field is treated as the STRING type. Now, you want to compute web session durations of users who visit your site, and you want to change its data type to the TIMESTAMP. You want to minimize the migration effort without making future queries computationally expensive. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Delete the table CLICK_STREAM, and then re — create it such that the column DT is of the TIMESTAMP type. Reload the data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a column TS of the TIMESTAMP type to the table CLICK_STREAM, and populate the numeric values from the column TS for each row. Reference the column TS instead of the column DT from now on.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a view CLICK_STREAM_V, where strings from the column DT are cast into TIMESTAMP values. Reference the view CLICK_STREAM_V instead of the table CLICK_STREAM from now on.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Add two columns to the table CLICK STREAM: TS of the TIMESTAMP type and IS_NEW of the BOOLEAN type. Reload all data in append mode. For each appended row, set the value of IS_NEW to true. For future queries, reference the column TS instead of the column DT, with the WHERE clause ensuring that the value of IS_NEW must be true.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Construct a query to return every row of the table CLICK_STREAM, while using the built — in function to cast strings from the column DT into TIMESTAMP values. Run the query into a destination table NEW_CLICK_STREAM, in which the column TS is the TIMESTAMP type. Reference the table NEW_CLICK_STREAM instead of the table CLICK_STREAM from now on. In the future, new data is loaded into the table NEW_CLICK_STREAM.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a car manufacturer and have set up a data pipeline using Google Cloud Pub/Sub to capture anomalous sensor events. You are using a push subscription in Cloud Pub/Sub that calls a custom HTTPS endpoint that you have created to take action of these anomalous events as they occur. Your custom HTTPS endpoint keeps getting an inordinate amount of duplicate messages. What is the most likely cause of these duplicate messages?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The message body for the sensor event is too large.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Your custom endpoint has an out-of-date SSL certificate.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The Cloud Pub/Sub topic has too many messages published to it.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Your custom endpoint is not acknowledging messages within the acknowledgement deadline.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is performing data preprocessing for a learning algorithm in Google Cloud Dataflow. Numerous data logs are being are being generated during this step, and the team wants to analyze them. Due to the dynamic nature of the campaign, the data is growing exponentially every hour.

The data scientists have written the following code to read the data for a new key features in the logs. 

BigQueryIO.Read
.named(“ReadLogData”)
.from(“clouddataflow-readonly:samples.log_data”)

You want to improve the performance of this data read. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Specify the TableReference object in the code.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use .fromQuery operation to read specific fields from the table.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use of both the Google BigQuery TableSchema and TableFieldSchema classes.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Call a transform that returns TableRow objects, where each element in the PCollexction represents a single row in the table.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company uses a proprietary system to send inventory data every 6 hours to a data ingestion service in the cloud. Transmitted data includes a payload of several fields and the timestamp of the transmission. If there are any concerns about a transmission, the system re-transmits the data. How should you deduplicate the data most efficiency?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Assign global unique identifiers (GUID) to each data entry.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Compute the hash value of each data entry, and compare it with all historical data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Store each data entry as the primary key in a separate database and apply an index.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Maintain a database table to store the hash value and other metadata for each data entry.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company built a TensorFlow neural-network model with a large number of neurons and layers. The model fits well for the training data. However, when tested against new data, it performs poorly. What method can you employ to address this?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Threading</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Serialization</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Dropout Methods</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dimensionality Reduction</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing the database schema for a machine learning-based food ordering service that will predict what users want to eat. Here is some of the information you need to store:

The user profile: What the user likes and doesn’t like to eat
The user account information: Name, address, preferred meal times
The order information: When orders are made, from where, to whom

The database will be used to store all the transactional data of the product. You want to optimize the data schema. Which Google Cloud Platform product should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these is NOT a way to customize the software on Dataproc cluster instances?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Set initialization actions</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Modify configuration files using cluster properties</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Configure the cluster using Cloud Deployment Manager</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Log into the master node and make changes from there</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which action can a Cloud Dataproc Viewer perform?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Submit a job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Delete a cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>List the jobs.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which Java SDK class can you use to run your Dataflow programs locally?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>LocalRunner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>DirectPipelineRunner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>MachineRunner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>LocalPipelineRunner</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What is the general recommendation when designing your row keys for a Cloud Bigtable schema?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Include multiple time series values within the row key</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Keep the row keep as an 8 bit integer</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Keep your row key reasonably short</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Keep your row key as long as the field permits</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Suppose you have a dataset of images that are each labeled as to whether or not they contain a human face. To create a neural network that recognizes human faces in images using this labeled dataset, what approach would likely be the most effective?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use K-means Clustering to detect faces in the pixels.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use feature engineering to add features for eyes, noses, and mouths to the input data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use deep learning by creating a neural network with multiple hidden layers to automatically detect features of faces.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Build a neural network with an input layer of pixels, a hidden layer, and an output layer with two categories.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to create a machine learning model that predicts the price of a particular stock based on its recent price history, what type of estimator should you use?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Unsupervised learning</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Regressor</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Classifier</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Clustering estimator</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these operations can you perform from the BigQuery Web UI?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Upload a file in SQL format.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Load data with nested and repeated fields.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Upload a 20 MB file.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Upload multiple files using a wildcard.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>When using Cloud Dataproc clusters, you can access the YARN web interface by configuring a browser to connect through a proxy.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>HTTPS</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>VPN</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>SOCKS</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>HTTP</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You decided to use Cloud Datastore to ingest vehicle telemetry data in real time. You want to build a storage system that will account for the long-term data growth, while keeping the costs low. You also want to create snapshots of the data periodically, so that you can make a point-in-time (PIT) recovery, or clone a copy of the data for Cloud Datastore in a different environment. You want to archive these snapshots for a long time. Which two methods can accomplish this? Choose 2 answers.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use managed export, and store the data in a Cloud Storage bucket using Nearline or Coldline class.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use managed export, and then import to Cloud Datastore in a separate project under a unique namespace reserved for that export.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use managed export, and then import the data into a BigQuery table created just for that export, and delete temporary export files.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write an application that uses Cloud Datastore client libraries to read all the entities. Treat each entity as a BigQuery table row via BigQuery streaming insert. Assign an export timestamp for each export, and attach it as an extra column for each row. Make sure that the BigQuery table is partitioned using the export timestamp column.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write an application that uses Cloud Datastore client libraries to read all the entities. Format the exported data into a JSON file. Apply compression before storing the data in Cloud Source Repositories.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>An online retailer has built their current application on Google App Engine. A new initiative at the company mandates that they extend their application to allow their customers to transact directly via the application. They need to manage their shopping transactions and analyze combined data from multiple datasets using a business intelligence (BI) tool. They want to use only a single database for this purpose. Which Google Cloud database should they choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud BigTable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to copy millions of sensitive patient records from a relational database to BigQuery. The total size of the database is 10 TB. You need to design a solution that is secure and time-efficient. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Export the records from the database as an Avro file. Upload the file to GCS using gsutil, and then load the Avro file into BigQuery using the BigQuery web UI in the GCP Console.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the records from the database as an Avro file. Copy the file onto a Transfer Appliance and send it to Google, and then load the Avro file into BigQuery using the BigQuery web UI in the GCP Console.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the records from the database into a CSV file. Create a public URL for the CSV file, and then use Storage Transfer Service to move the file to Cloud Storage. Load the CSV file into BigQuery using the BigQuery web UI in the GCP Console.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the records from the database as an Avro file. Create a public URL for the Avro file, and then use Storage Transfer Service to move the file to Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building a teal-lime prediction engine that streams files, which may contain Pll (personal identifiable information) data, into Cloud Storage and eventually into BigQuery You want to ensure that the sensitive data is masked but still maintains referential Integrity, because names and emails are often used as join keys How should you use the Cloud Data Loss Prevention API (DLP API) to ensure that the Pll data is not accessible by unauthorized individuals?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a pseudonym by replacing the Pll data with cryptogenic tokens, and store the non-tokenized data in a locked-down button.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Redact all Pll data, and store a version of the unredacted data in a locked-down bucket</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Scan every table in BigQuery, and mask the data it finds that has Pll</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a pseudonym by replacing Pll data with a cryptographic format-preserving token</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a shipping company that uses handheld scanners to read shipping labels. Your company has strict data privacy standards that require scanners to only transmit recipients’ personally identifiable information (PII) to analytics systems, which violates user privacy rules. You want to quickly build a scalable solution using cloud-native managed services to prevent exposure of PII to the analytics systems. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an authorized view in BigQuery to restrict access to tables with sensitive data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install a third-party data validation tool on Compute Engine virtual machines to check the incoming datafor sensitive information.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Stackdriver logging to analyze the data passed through the total pipeline to identify transactions that may contain sensitive information.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Build a Cloud Function that reads the topics and makes a call to the Cloud Data Loss Prevention API. Use the tagging and confidence levels to either pass or quarantine the data in a bucket for review.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You have historical data covering the last three years in BigQuery and a data pipeline that delivers new data to BigQuery daily. You have noticed that when the Data Science team runs a query filtered on a date column and limited to 30–90 days of data, the query scans the entire table. You also noticed that your bill is increasing more quickly than you expected. You want to resolve the issue as cost-effectively as possible while maintaining the ability to conduct SQL queries. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Re-create the tables using DDL. Partition the tables by a column containing a TIMESTAMP or DATE Type.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Recommend that the Data Science team export the table to a CSV file on Cloud Storage and use Cloud Datalab to explore the data by reading the files directly.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Modify your pipeline to maintain the last 30–90 days of data in one table and the longer history in a different table to minimize full table scans over the entire history.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write an Apache Beam pipeline that creates a BigQuery table per day. Recommend that the Data Science team use wildcards on the table name suffixes to select the data they need.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are a head of BI at a large enterprise company with multiple business units that each have different priorities and budgets. You use on-demand pricing for BigQuery with a quota of 2K concurrent on-demand slots per project. Users at your organization sometimes don’t get slots to execute their query and you need to correct this. You’d like to avoid introducing new projects to your account. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Convert your batch BQ queries into interactive BQ queries.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an additional project to overcome the 2K on-demand per-project quota.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Switch to flat-rate pricing and establish a hierarchical priority model for your projects.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the amount of concurrent slots per project at the Quotas page at the Cloud Console.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>An aerospace company uses a proprietary data format to store its night data. You need to connect this new data source to BigQuery and stream the data into BigQuery. You want to efficiency import the data into BigQuery where consuming as few resources as possible. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a standard Dataflow pipeline to store the raw data in BigQuery and then transform the format later when the data is used.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write a shell script that triggers a Cloud Function that performs periodic ETL batch jobs on the new data source</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Apache Hive to write a Dataproc job that streams the data into BigQuery in CSV format</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use an Apache Beam custom connector to write a Dataflow pipeline that streams the data into BigQuery in Avro format</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>A live TV show asks viewers to cast votes using their mobile phones. The event generates a large volume of data during a 3 minute period. You are in charge of the Voting restructure* and must ensure that the platform can handle the load and Hal all votes are processed. You must display partial results write voting is open. After voting doses you need to count the votes exactly once white optimizing cost. What should you do?

- Voters and Viewers
- Serving Platform
- Voting Infrastructure
    </question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Memorystore instance with a high availability (HA) configuration.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL database with high availability (HA) configuration and multiple read replicas.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write votes to a Pub Sub tope and have Cloud Functions subscribe to it and write voles to BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Write votes to a Pub/Sub topic and load into both Bigtable and BigQuery via a Dataflow pipeline. Query Bigtable for real-time results and BigQuery for later analysis. Shut down the Bigtable instance when voting concludes.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are selecting services to write and transform JSON messages from Cloud Pub/Sub to BigQuery for a data pipeline on Google Cloud. You want to minimize service costs. You also want to monitor and accommodate input data volume that will vary in size with minimal manual intervention. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataproc to run your transformation. Monitor CPU utilization for the cluster. Resize the number of worker nodes in your cluster via the command line.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataproc to run your transformation. Use the diagnose command to generate an operational output archive. Locate the bottleneck and adjust cluster resources.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow to run your transformation. Monitor the job system lag with Stackdriver. Use the default autoscaling setting for worker instances.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow to run your transformation. Monitor the total execution time for a sampling of job. Configure the job to use non-default Compute Engine machine types when needed.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are migrating an application that tracks library books and information about each book, such as author or year published, from an on-premises data warehouse to BigQuery In your current relational database, the author information is kept in a separate table and joined to the book information on a common key Based on Google's recommended practice for schema design, how would you structure the data to ensure optimal speed of queries about the author of each book that has been borrowed?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Keep the schema the same, maintain the different tables for the book and each of the attributes, and query as you are doing today</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table that is wide and includes a column for each attribute, including the author's first name, last name, date of birth, etc</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a table that includes information about the books and authors, but nest the author fields inside the author column</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Keep the schema the same, create a view that joins all of the tables, and always query the view</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your neural network model is taking days to train. You want to increase the training speed. What can you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Subsample your test dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Subsample your training dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the number of input features to your model.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the number of layers in your neural network.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You set up a streaming data insert into a Redis cluster via a Kafka cluster. Both clusters are running on Compute Engine instances. You need to encrypt data at rest with encryption keys that you can create, rotate, and destroy as needed. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a dedicated service account, and use encryption at rest to reference your data stored in your Compute Engine cluster instances as part of your API service calls.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create encryption keys in Cloud Key Management Service. Use those keys to encrypt your data in all of the Compute Engine cluster instances.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create encryption keys locally. Upload your encryption keys to Cloud Key Management Service. Use those keys to encrypt your data in all of the Compute Engine cluster instances.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create encryption keys in Cloud Key Management Service. Reference those keys in your API service calls when accessing the data in your Compute Engine cluster instances.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You want to migrate an on-premises Hadoop system to Cloud Dataproc. Hive is the primary tool in use, and the data format is Optimized Row Columnar (ORC). All ORC files have been successfully copied to a Cloud Storage bucket. You need to replicate some data to the cluster’s local Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) to maximize performance. What are two ways to start using Hive in Cloud Dataproc? (Choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Run the gsutil utility to transfer all ORC files from the Cloud Storage bucket to HDF. Mount the Hive tables locally.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Run the gsutil utility to transfer all ORC files from the Cloud Storage bucket to any node of the Dataproc cluster. Mount the Hive tables locally.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Run the gsutil utility to transfer all ORC files from the Cloud Storage bucket to the master node of the Dataproc cluste Then run the Hadoop utility to copy them do HDF. Mount the Hive tables from HDFS.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Leverage Cloud Storage connector for Hadoop to mount the ORC files as external Hive table. Replicate external Hive tables to the native ones.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the ORC files into BigQuery. Leverage BigQuery connector for Hadoop to mount the BigQuery tables as external Hive table. Replicate external Hive tables to the native ones.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are implementing security best practices on your data pipeline. Currently, you are manually executing jobs as the Project Owner. You want to automate these jobs by taking nightly batch files containing non-public information from Google Cloud Storage, processing them with a Spark Scala job on a Google Cloud Dataproc cluster, and depositing the results into Google BigQuery. How should you securely run this workload?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Restrict the Google Cloud Storage bucket so only you can see the files</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Grant the Project Owner role to a service account, and run the job with it</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a service account with the ability to read the batch files and to write to BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use a user account with the Project Viewer role on the Cloud Dataproc cluster to read the batch files and write to BigQuery</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You need to choose a database to store time series CPU and memory usage for millions of computers. You need to store this data in one-second interval samples. Analysts will be performing real-time, ad hoc analytics against the database. You want to avoid being charged for every query executed and ensure that the schema design will allow for future growth of the dataset. Which database and data model should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a table in BigQuery, and append the new samples for CPU and memory to the table</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a wide table in BigQuery, create a column for the sample value at each second, and update the row with the interval for each second</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Create a narrow table in Cloud Bigtable with a row key that combines the Computer Engine computer identifier with the sample time at each second</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a wide table in Cloud Bigtable with a row key that combines the computer identifier with the sample time at each minute, and combine the values for each second as column data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are migrating your data warehouse to Google Cloud and decommissioning your on-premises data center Because this is a priority for your company, you know that bandwidth will be made available for the initial data load to the cloud. The files being transferred are not large in number, but each file is 90 GB Additionally, you want your transactional systems to continually update the warehouse on Google Cloud in real time What tools should you use to migrate the data and ensure that it continues to write to your warehouse?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>true</valid>
          <detail>Storage Transfer Service for the migration, Pub/Sub and Cloud Data Fusion for the real-time updates</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>BigQuery Data Transfer Service for the migration, Pub/Sub and Dataproc for the real-time updates</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>gsutil for the migration; Pub/Sub and Dataflow for the real-time updates</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>gsutil for both the migration and the real-time updates</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
</bank>